AND GOOD AFTERNOON. WELCOME TO THE MAY 5TH 2026
REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
>> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL?
>> YES SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN
PRESENT SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER NOT PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMUD MAHMOOD NOT
PRESENT SUPERVISOR OR MANDOLIN PRESIDENT MANDOLIN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR
PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR
WALTON WALTON PRESENT SUPERVISOR WANG WANG PRESENT
MR. PRESIDENT YOU HAVE A QUORUM .
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL
HOMELAND OF THE ROMITA COLONY WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL
INHABITANTS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA AS THE
INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH
THEIR TRADITIONS THEIR AMATEUR SHALLOWNESS HAVE NEVER CEDED
LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR RESPONSABLE CITIES AS THE
CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO
RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL TERRITORY AS GUESTS WE
RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR
TRADITIONAL HOMELANDS. WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY
ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS, ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE
ROMITA ALONI COMMUNITY AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN
RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES. COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME
IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE YOUR REPUBLIC FOR
WHICH IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD?
>> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I'D LIKE TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. GOV TV TODAY THAT IS ESPECIALLY KALEENA MENDOZA.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS AND MAKE THE
TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
>> MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY COMMUNICATIONS?
YES. THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOUR ATTENDANCE HERE
IN PERSON AT THE BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE CHAMBER.
ROOM TWO 52ND FLOOR OF CITY HALL.
WHEN YOU CAN'T BE HERE, THE PROCEEDINGS ARE AIRING LIVE ON
S.F. GOV TV'S CHANNEL 26 OR LIVE STREAMING AT S.F. GOP TV
DAWG. YOU MAY SUBMIT PUBLIC COMMENT
IN WRITING BY SENDING AN EMAIL TO POST AT S.F. GOP.ORG OR VIA
U.S. POSTAL SERVICE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
. ONE DOCTOR CALL TIME BE GOOD
PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO CALIFORNIA NINE FOR 1
OR 2 TO MAKE A REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION FOR A FUTURE
MEETING UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT ORDER
REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANT PLEASE CONTACT THE CLERK'S
OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING
(415) 554-5184. FINALLY WE ARE IN RECEIPT OF
TWO MEMOS AS STATED OVER THE LAST SEVERAL WEEKS SUPERVISOR
FIELDER SUBMITTED A MEMO DATED APRIL 7TH REQUESTING TO BE
EXCUSED EACH WEEK BETWEEN APRIL 7TH IN MAY AND JUNE 30TH AND ON
MAY 4TH WE RECEIVED A MEMO MEMO FROM SUPERVISOR MAHMUD
REQUESTING BE EXCUSED FROM TODAY'S MEETING.
MEMBERS MR. PRESIDENT, THAT CONCLUDES MY COMMUNICATION
AND THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. >> COLLEAGUES, COULD I HAVE A
MOTION TO EXCUSE SUPERVISORS FIELDER AND MAHMOOD FROM
TODAY'S MEETING? MOTION MADE BY CHAN
AND SECONDED BY WALTON COLLEAGUES.
I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION. SUPERVISORS FIELDER AND MAHMOOD
ARE EXCUSED. AND THEN MADAM CLERK LET'S GO
TO OUR CONSENT TO AGENDA ITEMS ONE THROUGH FIVE ITEMS ONE
THROUGH FIVE ARE ON CONSENT. THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED
ROUTINE. >> IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM
MAY BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY.
>> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS ONE THROUGH FIVE
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN II MANDOLIN
I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EITHER NICE OR WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE
ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO
UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER SIX.
>> ITEM NUMBER SIX IS THE ORDINANCE RETROACTIVELY
AUTHORIZING THE POLICE DEPARTMENT TO ACCEPT AN
EXPENDED GRANT IN THE AMOUNT OF 6.22 5 MILLION FROM THE U.S.
DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE OFFICE OF COMMUNITY ORIENTED POLICING
SERVICES TO FUND 50 NEW POLICE OFFICER POSITIONS FOR
APPROXIMATELY FOR THE PERIOD OF OCTOBER 1ST 2025 THROUGH
SEPTEMBER 30TH 2030 AND AMENDING THE ANNUAL SALARY
ORDINANCE. I'M COLLEAGUES I THINK WE CAN
TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED. MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
SEVEN THROUGH NINE TOGETHER. >> ITEM SEVEN THROUGH 9 OR 3
ORDINANCES ADOPTING MEMORANDUM OF UNDERSTANDING TO BE
EFFECTIVE BETWEEN JULY 1ST 2026 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2030 BETWEEN
THE CITY AND FOR ITEM NUMBER SEVEN THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
OFFICERS ASSOCIATION FOR ITEM EIGHT THE SAN FRANCISCO
FIREFIGHTERS UNION LOCAL 798 IAF AFL-CIO UNIT TWO AND FOR
ITEM NINE WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO FIREFIGHTERS UNION
LOCAL 798 IAF F AFL CIO UNIT ONE I THINK WE CAN TAKE THESE
ITEMS SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER TEN. ITEM NUMBER TEN IS AN ORDINANCE
TEMPORARILY EXCLUDING CERTAIN SITES FROM THE PROVISIONS OF SB
79 THAT REQUIRE LOCAL JURISDICTIONS TO ALLOW
RESIDENTS SHOW USES ON SITES WITHIN ONE HALF MILE OF A
TRANSIT ORIENTED DEVELOPMENT STOP PERMANENTLY EXCLUDING
SITES LOCATED IN INDUSTRIAL EMPLOYMENT HUBS, AMENDING THE
PLANNING CODE TO PERMIT ADDITIONAL DENSITY AND HEIGHT
FOR RESIDENTIAL PROJECTS ON CERTAIN PARCELS WITHIN ONE HALF
MILE OF A TRANSIT ORIENTED DEVELOPMENT.
STOP ADOPTING AN ALTERNATIVE PLAN TO SB 79 AND MAKING
APPROPRIATE FINDINGS AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 11.
ITEM NUMBER 11 IS AN ORDINANCE AMENDING THE ADMINISTRATIVE
CODE TO AUTHORIZE THE SFM T TO ESTABLISH A CURBSIDE ELECTRIC
VEHICLE CHARGING STATION PERMIT PROGRAM AMENDING THE PUBLIC
WORKS CODE TO REFLECT THE AUTHORITY OF THE S.F. MTA TO
ISSUE PERMITS FOR THE CURBSIDE ELECTRIC VEHICLE CHARGING
STATION PROGRAM. AMENDING THE TRANSPORTATION
CODE TO AUTHORIZE S.F. MTA TO IMPOSE ADMINISTER RIDER
PENALTIES FOR VIOLATIONS AND MAKING APPROPRIATE FINDINGS
. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED.
MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO NEW BUSINESS ITEM NUMBER 12.
>> ITEM NUMBER 12 IS AN ORDINANCE APPROPRIATING 1.5
MILLION FROM THE GENERAL RESERVE TO THE PUBLIC DEFENDER
TO SUPPORT THE PROJECTED INCREASES IN SALARIES
AND FRINGE BENEFIT COSTS IN FISCAL YEAR 2025 TO 2026
AND PURSUANT TO CHARTER SECTION 9.1 13C THIS ORDINANCE REQUIRES
A TWO THIRDS APPROVAL OF ALL MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS 13 AND 14 TOGETHER ITEMS
13 AND 14 OR 2 RESOLUTIONS APPROVING AGREEMENTS WITH THE
DEPARTMENT OF DISABILITY AND AGING SERVICES.
ITEM 13 IS WITH HOLMBRIDGE INCORPORATED FOR CONTRACT MODE
IN-HOME SUPPORTIVE SERVICES INCREASING THE AGREEMENT AMOUNT
FOR A NEW TOTAL NOT TO EXCEED AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 158
MILLION WITH NO CHANGES TO THE ORIGINAL TERM AND EFFECTIVE
UPON APPROVAL OF THIS RESOLUTION.
AND ITEM 14 IS WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO IN-HOME SUPPORTIVE
SERVICES PUBLIC AUTHORITY FOR INDEPENDENT PROVIDER MODE
IN-HOME SUPPORTIVE SERVICES FOR A TERM OF FIVE YEARS FROM JULY
1ST 2026 TO JUNE 30TH 2031 AND FOR A TOTAL NOT TO EXCEED
AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 991 MILLION.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER 15. >> ITEM NUMBER 15 IS A
RESOLUTION RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZING THE DEPARTMENT OF
PUBLIC HEALTH TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND A GRANT INCREASE
FROM THE NATIONAL INSTITUTES OF HEALTH THROUGH FLORIDA STATE
UNIVERSITY FOR PARTICIPATION IN A PROGRAM ENTITLED
ADOLESCENT MEDICINE TRIALS NETWORK FOR HIV AIDS
INTERVENTIONS SCIENTIFIC LEADERSHIP CENTER FOR A TOTAL
AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 408,000 FOR THE TOTAL PERIOD OF JANUARY
25TH 2023 THROUGH JANUARY 14TH 2027.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL EVENT
PLEASE CALL ITEM 16. ITEM NUMBER 16 IS A RESOLUTION
RETROACTIVE AUTHORIZING THE OFFICE OF ECONOMIC
AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT TO ACCEPT AN EXPENDED GRANT IN THE
AMOUNT OF 50,000 FROM THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA.
CALIFORNIA NATIONAL RESOURCES AGENCY FOR AMERICANS WITH
DISABILITIES ACT. RESTROOM AND RESTROOM
IMPROVEMENTS AT THE CHARITY CULTURAL CENTER SERVICES CENTER
DURING THE FISCAL YEAR JULY 1ST, 2025 THROUGH JUNE 30TH
2026. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAME CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 17.
ITEM NUMBER 17 IS AN ORDINANCE AMENDING THE TRANSPORTATION
CODE TO AUTHORIZE THE DIRECTOR OF TRANSPORTATION TO APPROVE
TEMPORARY STREET USE PERMITS UNDER CERTAIN CIRCUMSTANCES
AMENDING THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO AUTHORIZE THE DIRECTOR
OF TRANSPORTATION TO APPROVE CERTAIN STREET CLOSURES
PROPOSED BY COMMUNITY BENEFITS DISTRICTS UNDER THE DOWNTOWN
ENTERTAINMENT EVENT ACTIVATION PROGRAM AND MAKING APPROPRIATE
FINDINGS. SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
MADAME CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 18.
>> ITEM NUMBER 18 IS AN ORDINANCE AMENDING THE HOUSING
CODE TO REVISE QUALIFICATIONS AND DEADLINES FOR CONDUCTING
STRUCTURAL MAINTENANCE INSPECTIONS AND MAKING
APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 19 ITEM NUMBER 19 IS AN
ORDINANCE CONDITIONALLY ACCEPTING AN OFFER OF
DEDICATION AND QUITCLAIM DEED FOR REAL PROPERTY FROM THE
OFFICE OF COMMUNITY INVESTMENT AN INFRASTRUCTURE FOR A SEGMENT
OF EAST CLEMENTINA STREET BETWEEN BEAL AND MAIN STREETS
FOR MAINTENANCE AND LIABILITY. CONDITIONALLY ACCEPTING OFFERS
OF IMPROVEMENTS FROM TRANSBAY TO FAMILY LP AND TRANSBAY TO
SENIOR LP WAIVING THE APPLICATION OF ORDINANCE NUMBER
1061 TO ALLOW ESTABLISHMENT EXPANSION AND REDUCTION OF
OFFICIAL SIDEWALK WASTE THROUGH ADMINISTRATIVE ACTION
ASSOCIATED WITH THE STREET SEGMENT AND TRANSBAY TO PUBLIC
IMPROVEMENTS AND MAKING APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM NUMBER 20. >> ITEM NUMBER 20 IS AN
ORDINANCE AMENDING THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO
AUTHORIZE THE PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION TO PURCHASE UTILITY
INFRASTRUCTURE FROM CUSTOMERS THAT THE PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION WOULD OTHERWISE BE REQUIRED TO INSTALL SUBJECT TO
SPECIFIED CONDITIONS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 21.
>> ITEM NUMBER 21 IS A RESOLUTION ADDING THE
COMMEMORATIVE STREET NAME HELEN WAKASA WAY TO JULIAN AVENUE
IN RECOGNITION OF HER LEGACY AS A FOUNDER OF FRIENDSHIP HOUSE
AND HER CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE NATIVE AMERICAN COMMUNITY
IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAME CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM 22. ITEM NUMBER 22 IS AN ORDINANCE
AMENDING THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO STATE THAT IT IS CITY
POLICY TO EXPAND THE AVAILABILITY A SITE BASED
PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING THAT PROHIBITS ON SITE ILLICIT
DRUG USE AMONG RESIDENTS BARRED THE CITY FROM FUNDING NEW SITE
BASED PCH FOR PEOPLE EXPERIENCING HOMELESSNESS THAT
PROHIBITS EVICTIONS ON THE BASIS OF DRUG USE ALONE
AND REQUIRE AGENCIES H S H TO SURVEY RESIDENTS OF SITE BASED
PCH TO ASSESS THEIR INTEREST IN LIVING IN EITHER DRUG
TOLERANT OR DRUG FREE H.S. >> CHAIR DORSEY THANK YOU
PRESIDENT MANDOLIN I'M COLLEAGUES I WOULD LIKE TO MAKE
A MOTION TO CONTINUE THIS ITEM FOR ONE WEEK APART FROM ONE OF
MY CO-SPONSORS BEING UNAVAILABLE TODAY I ALSO AM
ENCOURAGED BY CONVERSATIONS I'VE HAD WITH RECOVERY
COMMUNITY ALLIES IN THE MEDICAL COMMUNITY WHO BELIEVE THAT
THERE IS STILL COMMON GROUND TO FIND WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO
MARIN MEDICAL SOCIETY. AS I MENTIONED IN MY LETTER
YESTERDAY, I AM PROUD TO HAVE STOOD WITH THIS ORGANIZATION
OVER THE YEARS ON ISSUES LIKE DEFENDING OUR ENFORCEMENT OF
HEALTH WARNINGS FOR ADS FOR SUGARY BEVERAGES AS A PRIVATE
SECTOR CAMPAIGN STRATEGIST WHEN I WORKED WITH THE SUPERVISOR
WALTON AND OTHERS IN 2019 TO DEFEAT AN EFFORT BY JEWEL LABS
TO OVERTURN SOME OF OUR TOBACCO CONTROL LAWS, IT INCLUDES
LEGISLATION WE HAD WORKED ON TO EXPAND ACCESS TO BUPRENORPHINE
AND NARCAN AND ALSO FOR THEIR SUPPORT OF THE RECOVERY FIRST
ORDINANCE. SO I'D LIKE TO THINK THAT WE'VE
GOT SOME GOOD COMMON GROUND THAT WE CAN STAND ON AND I HAVE
MADE A COMMITMENT TO TWO COLLEAGUES THAT I'M GOING TO DO
EVERYTHING I CAN IN THE WEEK THAT WE HAVE TO FIND COMMON
GROUND. >> IT'S ALL RIGHT.
>> VICE VERSA HAS MADE A MOTION TO CONTINUE FOR ONE WEEK
SECONDED BY SUPERVISOR CHERYL. >> COLLEAGUES, CAN WE TAKE THAT
WITHOUT OBJECTION? WITHOUT OBJECTION.
THE MOTION PASSES. >> I WOULD NOTE THAT WE HAVE
BEEN JOINT I THINK IT'S REVEREND BROWN OUT THERE.
>> THERE IS I WOULD NOTE THAT WE'VE BEEN JOINED BY OUR FORMER
MEMBER OF THIS BOARD, REVEREND AMOS BROWN.
>> WELCOME. A LITTLE APPLAUSE.
VERY NICE. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER 23. >> ITEM NUMBER 23 IS A
RESOLUTION SUPPORTING AND RECOGNIZING THE IMPORTANCE
OF THE JUNIOR RESERVE OFFICERS TRAINING WORK PROGRAM
AND ENCOURAGING THE SAN FRANCISCO UNIFIED SCHOOL
DISTRICT TO CONTINUE TO PROVIDE HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS THE
OPPORTUNITY TO PARTICIPATE IN ENSURE THE PROGRAM IS
PRESERVED AS CURRENTLY CONSTITUTED.
>> SUPERVISOR WONG THANK YOU PRESIDENT GENTLEMEN CHERTSEY
HAS BEEN IN SAN FRANCISCO'S PUBLIC SCHOOLS FOR OVER 90
YEARS. TODAY IT OPERATES AT SIX HIGH
SCHOOLS BARBARA GALLO LINCOLN LAW MISSION AND WASHINGTON.
AND IT SERVES OVER 900 STUDENTS WHO WHO CHOOSE TO ENROLL
AND OVER 600 MORE WHO USE THE PROGRAMS PHYSICAL EDUCATION
OPTION. ENROLLMENT HAS GROWN FROM 350
STUDENTS THREE YEARS AGO TO OVER 900 TODAY.
THAT GROWTH IS HAPPENING BECAUSE THE STUDENTS
AND FAMILIES WHO MAKE THIS CHOICE FIND REAL VALUE IN IT.
THE PROGRAM TEACHES LEADERSHIP COMMUNICATION FIRST AID
CONFLICT MANAGEMENT, GOVERNMENT STRUCTURE, FINANCIAL LITERACY
AND OTHER SKILLS THAT PREPARE YOUNG PEOPLE FOR LIFE AFTER
HIGH SCHOOL. THE COST IS SHARED EQUALLY
BETWEEN THE ARMY AND THE SCHOOL DISTRICT AND THE PROGRAM DOES
NOT RECRUIT CADETS INTO JOINING THE MILITARY.
CADETS DESCRIBE THEIR JROTC COMMUNITY AS A SECOND FAMILY
AND AS A SAFE ENVIRONMENT WHERE THEY BELONG.
THAT IS A MEANINGFUL OUTCOME FOR ANY AFTER-SCHOOL OR
CO-CURRICULAR PROGRAM SERVING OVER 1000 KIDS IN THE CITY.
I WANT TO THANK YOU TWO SUPERVISORS DORSEY MANAGEMENT
MELGAR AND CHERYL FOR CO-SPONSORING AND I WANT TO
THANK THE OVER 100 CURRENT JROTC CADETS, PARENTS
AND SUPPORTERS WHO TOOK THE TIME TO WRITE TO THIS BOARD.
THE VOLUME OF CORRESPONDENCE REFLECTS THE VALUE OF THE
PROGRAM THAT PROVIDES AND THE STUDENTS LIVES.
THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR WALTON.
THANK YOU PRESIDENT AMENDMENT. I AM TRYING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
WE ARE DOING HERE. I DO THINK THAT JROTC IS A
PROGRAM THAT IS BENEFICIAL TO STUDENTS IN THE SCHOOL DISTRICT
BUT I ALSO KNOW AND IT IS NOT TRUE THAT THE COST IS SHARED
EQUALLY BY THE SCHOOL DISTRICT AND THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT, THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT AND THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT PAY FOR HALF THE
SALARIES OF THE EDUCATORS. BUT THE SCHOOL DISTRICT PAYS
100% OF THE BENEFITS FOR THAT POSITION AND 100% FOR ALL
EQUIPMENT ETC. FOR THE JROTC PROGRAM SUPPORT JROTC.
>> BUT I, I CAN'T SUPPORT SOMETHING THAT IS URGING THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT TO POSSIBLY SPEND MORE MONEY ON A PROGRAM
THAT IS A DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE PROGRAM.
SO I'M REALLY TRYING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT IS THE
RESOLUTION DOING HERE? WHAT ARE WE URGING THE DISTRICT
TO DO? ARE WE TELLING THEM TO USE MORE
SCHOOL DISTRICT RESOURCES FOR JROTC WHICH IS A FEDERAL
PROGRAM OR WHAT ARE WE TRYING TO ATTEMPT TO DO WITH THIS
RESOLUTION? >> I DON'T SEE ANYONE THE CUTE
SYMBOL ON OUR SON. >> I TO SEE SOMEONE IN THE
SUPERVISOR WHEN I PRESS THE WRONG BUTTON.
OKAY. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WALTON. THE PURPOSE OF THE RESOLUTION
IS TO SUPPORT THE CONTINUED PRESERVATION OF THE JROTC
PROGRAM. AS MANY HAVE SEEN IN PAST YEARS
AT THE SCHOOL DISTRICT, THE GERTIE SU PROGRAM HAS BEEN AT
RISK BEFORE IN BACK IN I THINK 2006 OR 2008 THE CITY PASSED I
THINK IT WAS PROPOSITION V SUPPORTING THE JROTC PROGRAM
IN IN OUR PUBLIC SCHOOLS AND TODAY THERE'S CONTINUED
SUPPORT AND ADVOCACY TO ENSURE THAT WE MAINTAIN OUR ROTC
PROGRAM AS IS DURING COMMITTEE. WE HAD INSTRUCTORS AND FORMER
STUDENTS COME AND SPEAK UP TO THE IMPORTANCE OF THIS PROGRAM
AND THEIR CONCERNS ABOUT ITS CONTINUED PRESERVATION IN THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT AND I'M HERE TO SUPPORT THAT.
>> THE JROTC PER BE ABLE TO REMAIN IN THE SCHOOL DISTRICT
AS CURRENTLY CONSTITUTED. >> SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU
PRESIDENT MELMAN SO JUST FOR MY CLARITY.
WE'RE NOT ASKING OR URGING THE SCHOOL DISTRICT TO SPEND
ANOTHER DIME ON JROTC. WE'RE JUST SUPPORTING THAT.
THE PROGRAM STAY AS IS. >> YES.
AS CURRENTLY CONSTITUTED THERE THERE IS NOT A REQUEST FOR MORE
FUNDING FOR THE PROGRAM. IT'S TO PRESERVE IT AS IS.
>> THANK. >> SUPERVISOR JAN THANK YOU.
I MEAN I THINK THAT IF THAT'S THE CASE WE WILL THERE BE
SURVEYS WONG IF WE'RE CONSIDER A FRIENDLY AMENDMENT ON PAGE
TWO LINE 20 THAT INDICATED FOR THAT CLAUSE THE CLAUSE IS
CURRENTLY STATED TO SAY RESOLVED THAT THE CITY
AND COUNTY ALSO FRANCISCO RECOGNIZES THE IMPORTANCE OF
THE JROTC PROGRAM ENCOURAGE EACH OF US TO CONTINUE TO
PROVIDE HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS THE OPPORTUNITY TO PARTICIPATE
PARTICIPATE IN JROTC AND TO ENSURE THE PROGRAM REMAINS
FULLY FULLY OPERATIONAL WHEN AS OF USD NO LONGER FACE BUDGET
DEFICIT. SO LIKE IN THE IN THE PAGE TWO
LINE 20 AFTER THE CLASS I SAY REMAIN FULLY OPERATIONAL WHEN
SUB USD NO LONGER FACES BUDGET DEFICIT OR EXPERIENCE BUDGET
DEFICIT MAY HAVE THESE AMENDMENTS BEEN SHARED WITH
SUPERVISOR WONG PRIOR TO THIS? NO.
>> BUT I MEAN I THINK THAT IF THIS IS SPRING UP I'M JUST KIND
OF BROKE. OKAY.
ALL RIGHT. >> WELL THIS WAS I'M HAPPY TO
DEFER CONSIDERATION OF THIS ITEMS LATER IN THE AGENDA IF
FOLKS WANT TO THINK ABOUT AMENDMENTS THIS WAS
IN COMMITTEE AMENDMENTS COULD HAVE BEEN MADE IN COMMITTEE.
SUPERVISOR WONG YOU CAN DEAL WITH US HOW YOU WANT TO IF
YOU'D LIKE A LITTLE MORE TIME THINK ABOUT PROPOSED AMENDMENTS
. UM I AM OPEN TO AMENDMENTS.
>> I JUST HAVEN'T SEEN IT SO FAR.
SO IF THERE'S A OKAY SO I'M GOING TO JUST SUGGEST THAT IF
SUPERVISORS WANT TO TALK ABOUT THIS SIDEBAR CONVERSATION
THAT'S FINE. WE CAN COME BACK.
LOOKS LIKE SUPERVISOR MELGAR MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING SHE WANT.
NOPE. OKAY.
ANYBODY OBJECT TO UP SUPPORT SUPERVISOR WALTON, YOU WANT TO
SAY SOMETHING? >> THANK YOU.
PRESENT AMENDMENT. I DEFINITELY DON'T OBJECT TO
MOVING FORWARD YOUR SUGGESTION I WOULDN'T EVEN MIND CONTINUING
THIS ITEM ANOTHER WEEK BUT REMEMBER YOU'RE CORRECT.
WE COULD HAVE ADDRESSED AMENDMENTS IN COMMITTEE.
>> IF YOU RECALL THIS CAME INITIALLY TO THE FULL BOARD TO
GO ON FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE WHICH I
DEFINITELY HAD A PROBLEM WITH THAT AND DEFINITELY THOUGHT IT
SHOULD HAVE GONE TO COMMITTEE AND I DID NOT THINK AS WE WERE
HAVING THIS CONVERSATION BEFORE IT GOT TO US THAT IT WILL COME
IN THIS SAME FORM. SO I APOLOGIZE FOR NOT
SUBMITTING ANY AMENDMENTS EARLIER BUT DEFINITELY WOULD
SUPPORT THE SUGGESTED AMENDMENT OF SUPERVISOR CHEN AND IF
SUPERVISOR ONE WANTS TO ADDRESS THIS DURING THIS MEETING OR
POSSIBLY CONTINUE IT TO NEXT WEEK, I'M DEFINITELY SUPPORTIVE
OF THAT. I'M TRYING I KNOW IT CAME TO
THE FACT I'M TRYING NOT TO VOTE NO ON THIS BUT I DO STRUGGLE
KNOWING THE SCHOOL DISTRICT BUDGET INTIMATELY WITH MAKING A
BLANKET STATEMENT SAYING WE SUPPORT ONE SPECIFIC PROGRAM
THAT AGAIN IS A FEDERAL PROGRAM IS PROBLEMATIC.
>> OKAY? SUPERVISOR ONE CAN THINK OF HE
CAN COUNT HE CERTAINLY CAN COUNT.
>> YOU CAN THINK ABOUT WHETHER HE WANTS TO TRY THIS DAY,
WHETHER HE WANTS TRY IT IN A WEEK WITH A CONTINUANCE,
WHETHER HE WANTS TO TRY TO AMEND TO POTENTIALLY GET, YOU
KNOW, UNANIMOUS FOR IT. >> I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GOING
ON. I LEAVE THIS IN HIS IN HIS
HANDS AND WE WILL AFTER SUPERVISOR CHERYL CONTINUE ON
WITH OTHER ITEMS AND COME BACK TO THIS.
>> YEAH I JUST THINK THIS IS HAD PLENTY OF TIME FOR
DISCUSSION THIS IS SILA THIS SO THAT AGAIN I THINK THIS IS HAD
PLENTY OF TIME FOR DISCUSSION OKAY SOUNDS LIKE SUPERVISOR
CHERYL IS READY TO VOTE BUT WE WILL TAKE IT UP LATER MADAM
CLERK YOU WANT PLEASE CALL ITEM 20 FOUR.
>> ITEM NUMBER 24 IS A RESOLUTION CONDEMNING AN
IMMIGRATION AND CUSTOMS ENFORCEMENT ACTION URGING THE
UNITED STATES CONGRESS TO FUND THE TRANSPORTATION AND SECURITY
AGENCY AND URGING SAN FRANCISCO LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES TO
CONTINUE TO ABIDE BY SANCTUARY CITY POLICIES.
I BELIEVE THAT WE'RE BACK TO BEING ABLE TO TAKE THIS SAME
HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL ITEM 25? >> ITEM 25 IS THE RESOLUTION
DETERMINING THAT THE ISSUANCE OF A TYPE 90 CONSUL GENERAL
MUSIC VENUE LIQUOR LICENSE TO THE MELLOW LLC TO DO BUSINESS
AS THE MELLOW S.F. LOCATED AT 1401 HAIGHT STREET WILL SERVE
THE PUBLIC CONVENIENCE OR NECESSITY OF THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND REQUESTING THAT THE
CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGE CONTROL
IMPOSE CONDITIONS ON THE ISSUANCE OF THE LICENSE SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, I THINK WE HAVE A
COMMITTEE REPORT. ITEM NUMBER 28 WAS HEARD BY THE
LAND USE AND TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING
ON MAY 4TH, 2026 AND WAS RECOMMENDED AS THE COMMITTEE
REPORT. >> IT IS A RESOLUTION APPROVING
THE OFFICIAL NAMING OF CERTAIN UNNAMED PUBLIC AND PRIVATE
STREETS AND THE PROPOSED RENAMING OF THE EXISTING BILL
WALSH WAY TO GIANTS DRIVE ALONG GILMAN PLAYGROUND PARK.
ALL RIGHT. AND WE'LL DO THIS SAME HOUSE,
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> AND MADAM CLERK, I THINK WE CAN DO TWO MINUTES OF ROLL
CALL. >> ALL RIGHT.
FIRST UP ON ROLL CALL IS SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> OH. >> OH, THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WALTON. SUPERVISOR WONG.
OKAY. TODAY.
OKAY. THERE IT IS.
COLLEAGUES, TODAY WE HONORED THE LIFE OF SUNSET RESIDENT JIM
GARCIA JR A PROUD SAN FRANCISCAN WHO PASSED AWAY ON
APRIL 15TH AT THE AGE OF 61 AFTER A LONG AND COURAGEOUS
BATTLE WITH CANCER, JIM WAS DEEPLY ROOTED IN THE SUNSET.
HE GREW UP IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD ATTENDING SAINTS OF CELIA
AND ST IGNATIUS AND LATER WENT ON TO THE UNIVERSITY OF SAN
FRANCISCO WHERE HE PLAYED DIVISION ONE TENNIS AND WAS
AMONG THE TOP PLAYERS ON HIS TEAM.
HIS LOVE FOR SPORTS STAYED WITH HIM THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE.
HE PLAYED IN LOCAL SOFTBALL GAMES FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS
AND GAVE BACK AS A COACH AT SAINT CECILIA MENTORING
GENERATIONS OF YOUNG PEOPLE INCLUDING HIS OWN CHILDREN.
AS A GENERAL CONTRACTOR, JIM HELPED BUILD HOMES ACROSS THE
SUNSET AND THROUGHOUT SAN FRANCISCO INCLUDING THE HOME
WHERE HE RAISED HIS FAMILY. HE TOOK PRIDE NOT ONLY IN THE
STRUCTURES HE BUILT BUT IN THE PEOPLE HE TAUGHT ALONG THE WAY.
HE SHARED HIS SKILLS GENEROUSLY TRAINING WITH YOUNG WORKERS
AND WORKING SIDE BY SIDE WITH HIS SON.
FOR JIM IT WAS NEVER JUST ABOUT THE WORK.
IT WAS ABOUT BUILDING SOMETHING LASTING AND BRINGING OTHERS
ALONG WITH HIM. MANY IN THE COMMUNITY ALSO KNEW
JIM THROUGH HIS PASSION FOR CARS FOR MEET UPS ALONG THE
GREAT HIGHWAY TO GATHERINGS AT SPEEDWAY MEADOW.
HE BROUGHT PEOPLE TOGETHER HIS LOVE FOR MEL PERS ESPECIALLY
HIS RED ROAD RUNNER WAS UNMISTAKABLE.
IT WAS NOT JUST A HOBBY IT WAS THE WAY HE CONNECTED WITH
OTHERS AND BUILT LASTING RELATIONSHIPS.
JIM WAS ALSO AN ATHLETE IN EVERY SENSE OF THE WORD FROM
TENNIS TO BASEBALL TO YEARS ON THE SOFTWARE ALL FIELD.
HE SHOWED UP WITH ENERGY, DISCIPLINE AND HEART.
AS COACH HE GAVE THAT SAME SPIRIT TO YOUNG PEOPLE ACROSS
THE SUNSET SHAPING NOT JUST PLAYERS BUT CONFIDENT
AND RESILIENT INDIVIDUALS. BUT ABOVE ALL, JIM WAS A
DEVOTED HUSBAND, FATHER, SON AND FRIEND.
HE SHARED 34 YEARS OF MARRIAGE WITH HIS WIFE THERESA
AND TOGETHER THEY RAISED RACHEL ANTONIO AND GINO IN THE SUNSET.
THE FACT THAT HE BUILT THEIR HOME WITH HIS OWN HANDS SAYS SO
MUCH ABOUT THE KIND OF MAN HE WAS.
STEADY, HARDWORKING AND DEEPLY COMMITTED TO HIS FAMILY.
WHAT STANDS OUT MOST IS HOW MANY PARTS OF THE SUNSET JIM
TOUCHED THE HOMES HE BUILT THE PLAYERS HE COACHED, THE FRIENDS
HE MADE, THE NEIGHBORS WHO KNEW THEY COULD COUNT ON HIM.
HIS LIFE BECAME PART OF THE FABRIC OF THE NEIGHBORHOOD IN A
QUIET BUT MEANINGFUL WAY. AND I WANT TO SHARE THIS IN THE
SUNSET SOME OF THE MOST MEANINGFUL LIVES ARE LIVED
QUIETLY. PEOPLE SHOW UP FOR THEIR
FAMILIES, THEIR NEIGHBORS AND THEIR COMMUNITY WITHOUT
EVER ASKING FOR RECOGNITION. THEY JUST GIVE DAY AFTER DAY.
THAT WAS JIM. HIS STRENGTH AND COURAGE
THROUGH HIS ILLNESS WERE AN INSPIRATION BUT IT IS THE WAY
HE LIVED WITH GENEROSITY PRIDE IN HIS WORK AND DEEP LOVE FOR
HIS FAMILY THAT WILL STAY WITH US.
ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD, WE EXTEND OUR DEEPEST CONDOLENCES
TO HIS WIFE TERESA, HIS CHILDREN RACHEL ANTONIO
AND GINO AND THE ENTIRE GARCIA FAMILY.
WE ARE GRATEFUL FOR JIM'S LIFE AND HE WILL BE DEEPLY MISSED
IN THE SUNSET AND ACROSS OUR CITY.
>> THANK YOU. THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR WONG SUPERVISOR.
>> LET'S SAY WE PROSECUTOR OUR 230.
ALL RIGHT. SO WE'LL COME BACK TO TWO ROLL
CALL. BUT MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU CALL
OUT 2:30 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER? >> YES, SIR.
SPECIAL ORDER AT 230 IS RECOGNITION ACCOMMODATIONS FOR
MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. AND AS HAS BECOME TRADITION FOR
THE FIRST TUESDAY OF AAPI HERITAGE MONTH, I WANTED TO
INVITE THE CO-CHAIR OF THE APA HERITAGE COMMITTEE TO COME ON
UP THE CHAIR CLAUDINE CHAMP, PRESIDENT OF THE APA HERITAGE
FOUNDATION AND CLAUDINE CHANG CO-CHAIR AL PEREZ.
YOUR PARTNERS IN CRIME WHO WE ALL KNOW AND LOVE ARE NOT HERE
BUT ARE HERE IN SPIRIT DENNIS YEE, GRACE ARCURI AND THOMAS
LEE CLAUDINE WHO WE ALL KNOW HAS BEEN THE DRIVING FORCE
BEHIND THE APA HERITAGE MONTH CELEBRATION FOR 21 YEARS.
IT'S BEEN RECOGNIZED NATIONWIDE EVERY DAY SINCE 1978.
SAN FRANCISCO'S CELEBRATIONS BEGAN IN 2005 WHEN CLAUDINE
FIRST PITCHED THE IDEA TO MAYOR GAVIN NEWSOM.
AND IT IS AN AMAZING, WONDERFUL CITYWIDE CELEBRATION WITH FILM
SCREENINGS AND AUTHOR READINGS AND CUISINE AND DANCES
AND PERFORMING ARTS AND WE ARE GRATEFUL TO YOU FOR DOING IT
YEAR AFTER YEAR AND WE WANTED TO WELCOME YOU TO TELL US
WHAT'S GOING ON THIS YEAR FLOODING THANK YOU.
>> BOARD PRESIDENT OWN AND SIMPLIFY THIS YOU MUST HAVE
READ OUR CELEBRATION GUIDE IT SEEMS THAT YOU DESCRIBE MANY OF
THE EVENTS SUPERVISOR SO YES THIS IS AAPI HERITAGE MONTH
AGAIN AND WE ARE SO EXCITED THIS YEAR BECAUSE OF THE
EFFORTS OF THE COMMITTEE WE HAVE OVER 100 PROGRAMS
THROUGHOUT THE MONTH OF MAY AND IN THE MANY NEIGHBORHOODS
I, I REVIEW THAT THERE'S SOMETHING FOR EVERYBODY TO
ENJOY AND THE THEME THIS YEAR IS ELEVATING CULTURES,
ELEVATING CULTURES IS THIS REALLY A CALL TO ACTION, A CALL
TO ACTION THAT REALLY DOES NEED TO DO MORE TO THAT TO EXPECT OF
THAT WE NEED TO DO MORE TO AMPLIFY THE INDIVIDUAL UNIQUE
CULTURAL HERITAGE OF EACH OF THE AAPI ETHNIC GROUP.
AND AT THE SAME TIME WE ALSO WANT TO AMPLIFY WHAT THE GROUP
LOOKS LIKE WHEN WE COME TOGETHER.
>> WE DO AAPI COMMUNITY. IT REALLY MAKES UP A VERY
BEAUTIFUL FABRIC FOR THIS OF THE CITY.
AND SO I THINK THAT WHILE WE APPRECIATE THE UNIQUENESS OF
EACH, WE ALSO WANT TO CELEBRATE THE TOGETHERNESS OF OUR MANY
ETHNIC GROUPS TOGETHER. FOR MANY OF YOU AND I THINK ALL
OF YOU HAVE BEEN TO OUR EVENTS IN THE PAST AND IN RECENT
YEARS. OUR INITIATIVES INCLUDE
NEIGHBORHOOD ACTIVATION BECAUSE WE THINK THAT WE REALLY MUST
SPREAD THE LOVE AROUND. SO YOU'LL HEAR FROM US IN A
COUPLE IN A COUPLE OF MINUTES SECONDS IS GOING TO TALK ABOUT
A NEIGHBORHOOD OUTREACH PROGRAM THAT HAVE BEGAN IN ONE
NEIGHBORHOOD NOW INTO FIVE NEIGHBORHOODS.
WE ARE ALSO VERY PROUD TO SHARE WITH YOU OUR YOUTH ENGAGEMENT
EFFORTS BECAUSE IT'S NOTHING MORE IMPORTANT TO OUR COMMUNITY
THAN TO NURTURE THE NEXT GENERATION OF YOUTH LEADERS
STARTING LAST YEAR WE HAVE A GROUP UP WHAT DO YOU CALL IT?
>> ARE YOU YOU AAPI YOUTH ADVISORS?
THEY ARE THE ONES THAT MANAGED THE PROGRAM THAT IS CALLED THE
AAPI YOUTH CHANGEMAKERS. >> SO WHAT AND THIS REALLY HAS
BECOME A VERY GOOD OPPORTUNITIES THAT WE HAVE
CREATED FOR MEMBERS OF THAT ADVISORY GROUP AND WORKING
IN CLOSE WITH IN CLOSE COOPERATION WITH THE SAN
FRANCISCO YOUTH COMMISSION AND WE ARE VERY EXCITED TO HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO PUT A LAUNCH DATE LAST YEAR AND TO CONTINUE IT
THIS YEAR AND SOME OF THE HIGHLIGHTS IN THE CELEBRATION
GUIDE YOU CAN ALL FIND OUT MORE ABOUT OUR PROGRAMS AT APA S.F.
DOT ORG. BUT I MUST SAY THAT THIS YEAR
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A COUPLE OF INTERESTING THINGS.
THIS IS THE FIRST YEAR THAT WE WILL INVITE YOU TO CELEBRATE
AAPI MONTH ON THE WATER ON THE WATER AND WOMEN IT BECAUSE OF
THE PARTNERSHIP WITH SEE YOU I SEE YOU ALL INVITED TO GET ONTO
THE DRAGON BOAT AND TO TO PADDLE WITH US.
>> IT WILL BE A LOT OF FUN. IT WILL BE AT LAKE MORISSET
THIS SATURDAY AT NOONTIME PRESS MEDIA SARAH WANG CONVINCE ME
AND ASSURE ME THAT NO SWIMMING EXPERIENCE NEEDED AS LONG AS
YOU CAN BALANCE YOURSELF IN THE BOAT BUT REALLY IT'S GOING TO
BE A LOT OF FUN. IS IT GOING TO BE A GREAT
FAMILY FUN EVENT AND I HOPE THAT MANY OF YOU AND IF YOU CAN
MAKE IT TO TO TIME AND TO DO THAT I ALSO WANT TO JUST CALL
OUT TO ONE IMPORTANT EVENT AND THAT IS THE CANTONESE OPERA
SING ALONG. AND I KNOW THAT A NUMBER OF TO
SUPERVISE THIS YOU HAVE BEEN PRACTICING AND I THINK YOU'LL
BE IT WAS REALLY GOING TO BE GREAT FUN I THINK THERE ARE SO
MANY ASPECTS OF OUR CULTURAL HERITAGE THAT ALTHOUGH WE HAVE
BEEN DOING THIS FOR 22 YEARS, EVERY YEAR WE FIND SOMETHING
SOMETHING NEW, SOMETHING TO OH WE HAVEN'T WE HAVEN'T DONE
THAT. >> WE HAVEN'T AMPLIFIED THAT
THIS YEAR HAVING YOU KNOW, FOCUS ON THAT.
SO I THINK IT IS REALLY AMAZING WHAT COLLECTIVELY WE CAN DO
TOGETHER. >> SO BEFORE I TURN TO OUR
CULTURE OUR POOREST WE TO COMMITTEE ONLY HAVE TO ASK FROM
ALL OF YOU ONE IS TO ATTEND AS MANY EVENTS AS YOU CAN IN YOUR
DISTRICT AND AND AND ALSO THROUGHOUT THE CITY AND COUNTY
OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> PLEASE DO BECAUSE IT WILL BE
ALWAYS GOOD TO SEE YOU THERE WITH YOUR PRESENCE OR YOUR
SUPPORT AND THE SECOND OSCARS FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE A
NEWS LETTER AND I KNOW MANY OF YOU DO.
>> PLEASE DO SPREAD THE WORD ABOUT CELEBRATING AAPI HERITAGE
MONTH. >> ALL OF YOUR OFFICES HAVE
RECEIVED OUR PUBLICITY TOOLKIT PREPARED BY THOMAS LEE AND I
HOPE THAT YOU WOULD TAKE THE OPPORTUNITY TO HELP US AMPLIFY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. AND HERE IS MY PARTNER IN CRIME
ELLE US. >> THANK YOU CLAUDINE HELLO
BOYS SUPERVISOR MY NAME IS ALBERT THIS AND IN ADDITION TO
AP HERITAGE MONTH WE ALSO CELEBRATE SAN FRANCISCO'S SMALL
BUSINESS WEEK. SO WE WANT TO INVITE YOU ALL TO
DINE LOCAL AND EAT GLOBAL AT THIS PROJECT.
>> SO WE CALL IT CHOW FUN. IT'S A CULTURAL CULINARY
FESTIVAL IN NEIGHBORHOODS AND EXCELSIOR OCEAN AVENUE
AND GENEVA AVENUE VISITATION VALLEY AND THIS YEAR EXPANDING
INTO PORTALES AND IT'S A WAY FOR US TO CELEBRATE SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS, LOCAL MERCHANTS WE'RE CALLING IT A
DINE AROUND INSTEAD OF RESTAURANT WEEK BECAUSE WE WANT
TO BE INCLUSIVE OF MOM AND POP BAKERIES, BOBA CAFES AND BARS.
THEY'RE NOT TRADITIONALLY CALLED RESTAURANTS SO WE'RE
CALLING IT DINE AROUND. IT'S FOR TWO WEEKS MAY 2 TO 16
AND SO YEAH, WE HAVE THIS PASSPORT PROGRAM TO ENCOURAGE
AS MANY OF YOU ALL TO SUPPORT MANY RESTAURANTS EVERY TIME YOU
MAKE A PURCHASE TO GET A SNAP OF YOUR PASSPORT AND YOU NEED
ONLY FOUR STAMPS TO QUALIFY FOR SOME VERY EXCITING PRIZES.
SO WE WOULD INVITE EVERYONE TO THIS CITY TO COME OUT TO THIS
TO OUR SIDE OF THE CITY AND I THINK SUPERVISORS CHAN CHAN FOR
YOUR STRONG SUPPORT FOR THIS PROGRAM IT'S GOING TO BE A LOT
OF FUN SO PLEASE COME OUT AND SUPPORT LOCAL MERCHANTS
AND CULTURE IN OUR SITE. >> THANK YOU.
>> WE ASK YOU TO ASSOCIATE OH YEAH.
SO THIS YEAR WE ARE WE HAVE 71 PARTICIPATING MERCHANTS ACROSS
THE EXCELSIOR OUR OCEAN AVENUE GENEVA AVENUE VISITATION VALLEY
AND PORTOLA. >> SO YES, JUST AMAZING
DIVERSITY OF OF CULTURES AND ETHNICITIES IN THIS PART OF
THE CITY. SO WE'D LOVE YOU ALL TO TRY
LIKE IT'S ALMOST LIKE TRAVELING AROUND THE WORLD JUST THROUGH
CUISINE SO PLEASE COME CHECK US OUT OR OUR WEBSITE IS CHAO FUN
S.F. DOT COM THANK YOU AND LAST BUT LONELY SO FOR THOSE OF YOU
WHO HAVE NOT SIGN UP FOR OUR CANTONESE OPERA SING ALONG IT'S
NEVER TOO LATE PLEASE TALK TO ME OR FIND ME SOMEWHERE AND OR
EMAIL ME TEXT ME AND WE'LL GET YOU BE TO BE A PART OF IT I
PROMISE YOU'LL BE GREAT FUN. >> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU BOTH. I'LL LEAVE BEHIND SOME
PASSPORTS SO YOU GUYS CAN ALL GET A COPY AND EXPERIENCE CHOW
FUN IN THAT AREA. ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW NIGHT AT HERBST THEATER.
THANK YOU. AND NOW WE WILL RESPOND TO WE
WILL RETURN TO OUR REGULARLY SCHEDULED PROGRAMING WITH
DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN. THANK YOU FOR PRESSING COMES UP
CHILDLINE COME TO VISIT DISTRICT 11 AS WELL.
>> COLLEAGUES, MAY I ASK SUZANNE RETURN NORMAN TO COME
TO THE PODIUM? >> COLLEAGUES I'M VERY PROUD TO
KICK OFF AAPI HERITAGE MONTH BY HONORING YAO GONG ONE SAN
FRANCISCO TODAY A PIONEER OF WORLD CLASS LION DANCE IN SAN
FRANCISCO AND INTERNATIONALLY YAO GORMAN HAS OPERATED FOR
OVER 50 YEARS IN SAN FRANCISCO ,SETTING THE GOLD STANDARD FOR
LION DANCE PERFORMANCES WINNING COMPETITION LOCALLY
AND INTERNATIONALLY. DEREK IT'S WOAI WITH SCHOOLS
IN THE UNITED STATES, HONG KONG ,AUSTRALIA AND CANADA THEIR
LION DANCES HAVE BEEN A HIGHLIGHT TO OVER 43 LUNAR NEW
YEAR PARADES, COUNTLESS GRAND OPENING CELEBRATIONS
AND CULTURAL EVENTS. YAO GORMAN'S OUTSTANDING
PERFORMANCE AS SPRING'S IMMENSE POSITIVITY, CULTURAL PRIDE
AND HOPE TO OUR COMMUNITY, GRANDMA SAID BEAUTY HAS BEEN
OUR INTEGRAL LEADER IN BOTH SAN FRANCISCO ALGONQUIN
AND CHINATOWN COMMUNITIES AND WAVERING SUPPORTING THE
PRESERVATION AND ACHIEVEMENT AND ADVANCEMENT OF ART
AND CULTURE. THE CURRENT GENERATION OF THE
ALGONQUIN IS LED BY THREE FIERCE AND DEDICATED MASTERS
SUSAN YI RITUAL OUT AND NORMAN LAO AND NORMAN.
IT'S A PROUD MEMBER OF DISTRICT 11.
THEY CONTINUE TO GUIDE AND MENTOR OUR FUTURE
GENERATION OF STUDENTS TIRELESSLY SUPPORTING THE
PRESERVATION AND ADVANCEMENT OF THEIR MARTIAL ART.
>> SUSAN IS THE ONLY FEMALE YOGA MASTER UNDER HER
INSTRUCTION A PROMISING GENERATION OF YOUNG WOMEN
STUDENTS ARE EMERGING WINNING GOLD AND SILVER MEDALS.
>> MASTER RICHER HAS DEDICATED OVER 25 YEARS PRESERVING
AND TEACHING YAO GONG ONCE IN CHINATOWN AND SUNSET
DISTRICT ACTIVELY CONTRIBUTING TO COMMUNITY EVENTS AND CULTURE
EDUCATION. MASTER NORMAN FANG LION DANCE
ME TWO EVENTS MODERN LION DANCE WHY PRESERVING TRADITIONAL
YANGON FOUNDATIONS HE HAS CREATED PROGRAMS
AND OPPORTUNITY TO EMPOWER YOUTH LEADERSHIP.
LION DANCE ME HAS BEEN INCREDIBLY SUCCESSFUL
IN COMPETITION LOCALLY AND INTERNATIONALLY.
IN 2023 LION DANCE ME WANT THE WESTERN LION KING TITLE AT THE
GENTING WORLD LION DANCE CHAMPIONSHIP IN MALAYSIA.
>> ALSO AS A DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR I'M INCREDIBLY PROUD
TO HAVE NORMAN FROM OUR DISTRICT UNDER TODAY LEADERSHIP
YAO GONG WILL CONTINUE TO THRIVE AND BRING THE PEOPLE
TOGETHER IN UNITY. WHETHER IT'S YOU'VE EXPLORING
MARTIAL ARTS IN LION DANCING FOR ITS FIRST TIME OR SENIORS
AND FAMILY WATCHING A PERFORMANCE IN THEIR
NEIGHBORHOOD, YAO GOLDWIN CONTINUES TO ENRICH OUR
CULTURAL LANDSCAPE AND STRENGTHENING OUR COMMUNITY
BONDS. I AM ALSO INTRODUCING A
RESOLUTION TODAY TO RECOGNIZE MAY 15TH, 2026 YAO GONG ONE DAY
IN SAN FRANCISCO TO CELEBRATE YOAKAM WINS CONTRIBUTION
AND DEDICATION TO CHINESE CULTURAL HERITAGE EDUCATION
AND COMMUNITY. >> AND I WILL ALSO SAY A FEW
WORDS IN CHINESE THIS IS LIKE THIS ARE THE WORDS THAT WE
OFTEN HEAR WHEN YOU HAVE A LION DANCE AND JOG IN THIS LONG
TONGUE SAY HI WISEMAN PERFORM COME SEE HIM AND SAY HEY
THOMPSON HOME GOODS AND TIN DAY LONG SEE YOUNG WHITE YET THE
TEEN TAKE HOME ONE DON'T TELL ETIM SOMEWHAT TALL YOU CAN
COUNT ON SOMETIMES SEE HOW SAY YOU FONG LA FOLK LONG HUNG TIN
HA SEE MORE KIM KWAN SING SEE HAZY YIP PING WONG HAIKOU LONG
TUNG CEO AUDIE COMITATO GET MORE LOMO SI NANCY HAI HOY
TITLE YELLOW GHETTO MEAN GANGADHAR YOU DON'T GET HOME ON
FINE TUNE GET HOME I SAY QUIT GETTING SUN LONG SEA SALT OR
TISSUE DILATE GET DON'T HATE TO DOHA DOHA SING TO ANGELIC LAND
YOU IN SOME FANCY JOSE COME ALONG YOUNG TOM WE WERE LIKE
JOSE SING SIA YO YOU WANT ACTING LADY SUPERVISORS SAUDER
THANK YOU PRESIDENT GENTLEMEN AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHEN
WHAT A APT RECOGNITION AND FOR THIS MONTH I JUST WANT TO ADD
MY QUICK APPRECIATION AND REALLY MY ALL OF YOUR WORK
IT IS ALWAYS A JOY TO SEE YOUR PERFORMANCES AND YOU KNOW MY
FAVORITE PART AND I SAW THIS THIS WEEKEND AS WELL AT THE
SEEING A LION DANCE MY FAVORITE PART IS THE BEGINNING OF A
PERFORMANCE OR A SHOW OR A GRAND OPENING.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE THERE'S A FEW PEOPLE AROUND BUT THEN QUICKLY
WHEN THE ENERGY PICKS UP AND WHEN THE NOISE STARTS
REVERBERATING THROUGHOUT THE STREETS OF CHINATOWN, ALL OF A
SUDDEN YOU SEE A CROWD JUST FORM AND YOU SEE PEOPLE WHO ARE
LOCAL COMING JUST FROM DOWN THE STREET.
BUT THEN YOU SEE PEOPLE COMING ALL THE WAY DOWN GRAND AVENUE
AND IT'S JUST SUCH A SIGHT TO BEHOLD AND I WILL NEVER GET
TIRED OF IT. SO THANK YOU FOR YOUR YOUR
WORK. THANK YOU FOR WHAT YOU DO TO
REALLY BRING THE YOUTH IN. IT'S ALWAYS SO AMAZING FOR ME
AS WELL TO JUST SEE YOU KNOW WITHIN WITHIN THESE COSTUMES
AND WITHIN THE LION DANCE YOU HAVE KIDS OF ALL AGES AND JUST
WHAT AN INCREDIBLE WHAT LESSONS THEY ARE LEARNING BOTH THE
PHYSICAL STAMINA AND THE STRENGTH OF LION DANCE BUT ALSO
JUST ALL OF THE WORK OF COLLABORATION AND OF TEAMWORK
AND RESPONSIBILITY. SO THANK YOU FOR ALL YOUR WORK
AND NOW THE FLOOR IS YOURS. GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS TO
THINK DISTINGUISHED GUESTS ELDERS, SEAFOOD STUDENTS
AND FRIENDS ON BEHALF OF A LOCAL WHEN KUNG FU SPORTS
ASSOCIATION USA WE ARE DEEPLY HONORED TO ACCEPT THIS SPECIAL
ACCOMMODATION TODAY WE ARE SINCERELY GRATEFUL TO THE CITY
OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR RECOGNIZING NOT JUST OUR
ORGANIZATION BUT THE RICH TRADITION OF CHINESE MARTIAL
ART THAT'S BEEN PASSED DOWN THROUGH GENERATIONS.
YOUR ARGUMENT IS MORE THAN JUST KUNG FU AND LINE DANCE IS A
SYSTEM THAT CULTIVATES DISCIPLINE, RESPECT,
PERSEVERANCE AND A STRONG SENSE OF COMMUNITY.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO PAY MY DEEPEST RESPECTS TO OUR
PREDECESSORS AND TEACHERS ESPECIALLY GRANDMASTERS WANG
CHUNG, TANJUNG CHOON GUAN DUK BILL LEE, DERRICK LEE, MICHAEL
LAO AND DAVID LUI. THEIR GUIDANCE SACRIFICE
DEDICATION HAVE ALLOWED THIS TRADITION TO CONTINUE TO GROW
HERE IN THE UNITED STATES. THIS RECOGNITION ALSO BELONGS
TO OUR STUDENTS FAMILIES AND SUPPORTERS MANY OF THEM
TRAINED QUIETLY AND CONSISTENTLY NOT FOR
RECOGNITION BUT FOR PERSONAL GROWTH.
THROUGH THEIR EFFORTS THEY CARRY FOR THE VALUES OF
HUMILITY, STRENGTH AND INTEGRITY INTO THEIR DAILY
LIVES HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO, ESPECIALLY WITHIN CHINATOWN.
ORGANIZATIONS LIKE OURS SERVE AS BOARD AND TRAINING HALLS.
THERE ARE PLACES WHERE CULTURE IS PRESERVED, WHERE GENERATIONS
CONNECT AND WHERE YOUNG PEOPLE FIND DIRECTIONS CONFIDENCE
AND PURPOSE. WE ACCEPT THIS COMBINATION WITH
GRATITUDE AND ALSO OFFER A NEW SENSE OF RESPONSIBILITY TO
CONTINUE TEACHING, TO CONTINUE SERVING OUR COMMUNITY AND TO
REPRESENT OUR CULTURE WITH HONOR AND RESPECT.
THANK YOU SUPERVISORS AND THANK YOU FOR THE CITY OF SAN
FRANCISCO FOR THIS MEANINGFUL RECOGNITION OF HELLO.
>> AND FIRST OF ALL, IT'S EXCITING WHEN I WALK INTO THIS
ROOM AND I GET TO SEE ALL THESE FACES IN A DIFFERENT ATMOSPHERE
BECAUSE USUALLY I SEE YOU AT A LOT OF MANY EVENTS.
SUPPORTING ALL OF THE COMMUNITY EVERYWHERE YOU GO TIRELESSLY AS
SUPERVISORS AND OFFICIALS OF OUR CITY.
SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH AND I'M JUST SO VERY THANKFUL THAT OUR
OUR GROUP GETS TO BE KNOW GET TO GET TO HAVE A DAY TWO TO BE
RECOGNIZED AND I CAN'T BE ANY HAPPIER BECAUSE I'VE BEEN
IN THIS FOR 40 YEARS AND I REMEMBER AS A89 YEAR OLD KID
JOINING. >> AND I SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE
IN THE ROOM FROM CLAUDINE TO SELF-HELP AND ELDERLY AND ANNIE
WHO'S NOT HERE WHERE WE GOT OUR FIRST OPPORTUNITY AND I
REMEMBER BEING IN CHINATOWN IT'S LIKE A SAFE HAVEN WHERE
YOU COME TO A COMMUNITY AS A KID NOT KNOWING WHAT LIFE IS.
IT GIVES YOU GUIDANCE, YOU KNOW?
RIGHT. AND THAT GUIDANCE HAS BEEN
INSTRUMENTAL IN MY LIFE AND IT'S SOMETHING THAT HAS
ENCOURAGED ME TO UNDERSTAND HOW TO GIVE BACK.
AND I'M JUST SO PROUD TO BE ABLE TO PASS IT ON AND I'M VERY
THANKFUL FOR MY IMMEDIATE FAMILY AND SEAFOODS
AND EVERYONE WHO HAVE DEFINITELY SUPPORTED ME ALONG
THE WAY AS WELL AS A COMMUNITY .
THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN A HUGE PART AND I THINK EVERYONE
IN THIS ROOM SETS A GREAT EXAMPLE OF COMING TOGETHER IN A
COMMUNITY AND THEY HAVE DIFFERENCES.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT WE ALWAYS GROW AND I FEEL THAT AND THAT
WHAT'S MAKES ME TRY TO BE BETTER FOR THE CITY TOO.
SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH. >> THANK YOU
. I JUST MADE SOMETHING.
YEAH BUT DON'T MAKE IT VERY BIG .
>> DISTRICT ONE SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MAN DOMAIN
TODAY COLLEAGUES IN HONOR OF API HERITAGE MONTH I WOULD LIKE
TO RECOGNIZE MR. DALEY AND MR. DALEY HAS BEEN A LEADER IN THE
CHINATOWN COMMUNITY FOR OVER FIVE DECADES.
>> HE HE HAS BEEN A A GREAT MEMBER OF THE CHINESE
CONSOLIDATED BENEVOLENT ASSOCIATION, ALSO KNOWN AS CCP
FOR HOLDING MANY ROLES INCLUDING THE FORMER PRESIDENT
A PRESIDING PRESIDENT, FORMER PRESIDENTS OF NINGBO BENEVOLENT
ASSOCIATION, CHINESE HOSPITAL BOARD MEMBER AND VICE CHAIR OF
THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES AT THE CENTRAL CHINESE HIGH SCHOOL.
CCP IS ONE OF THE OLDEST UMBRELLA ORGANIZATIONS
IN CHINESE AMERICAN COMMUNITY INITIALLY ESTABLISHED TO
PROVIDE ESSENTIAL SERVICES, FIGHT DISCRIMINATION, PROMOTE
CHINESE CULTURE AND ORGANIZE COMMUNITY AFFAIRS DURING TIMES
OF INTENSE HOSTILITY AND RACISM CRITICAL WORK THAT THEY
CONTINUE TO DO TODAY KPA WAS GALVANIZED BY THE LANDMARK
SUPREME COURT CASE U.S. VERSUS WONG KIM ARK, WHICH THE COURT
LATER RULED IN FAVOR OF THE COMMUNITY THE CHINESE-AMERICAN
COMMUNITY AND HELP ENSHRINE BIRTHRIGHT CITIZENSHIP FOR
EVERYONE THE VERY SAME RIGHT THAT IS BEING THREATENED AGAIN
BY THE CURRENT TRUMP ADMINISTRATION.
MR. DALEY IMMIGRATED FROM HONG KONG TO SAN FRANCISCO WITH HIS
FAMILY IN THE 1970S. HE FIRST JOINED CCP BECAUSE HIS
FATHER WAS PART OF THE LEADERSHIP TEAM.
DENG WAS FATHER'S HIS FATHER'S CHAUFFEUR WAITING IN THE CAR
UNTIL HIS FATHER WAS DONE WITH MEETINGS AND BANQUETS OFTEN AT
THE HISTORIC FAR EAST CAFE WHICH UNCLE BILLY WAS I THINK
HE WAS HERE EARLY ON TO AND IT'S ALSO WHERE UNCLE BILLY
MANAGES MR. DENG LEE'S FATHER THOUGHT IT WAS A WASTE OF TIME
FOR DANE TO WAIT AROUND. HE SUGGESTED THAT HE JOIN CCP
AND HE QUICKLY BECAME ONE OF THE LEADERS DURING THE COVID 19
PANDEMIC DENG WAS ONE OF THE ORGANIZERS OF THE FIRST
ANTI-ASIAN HATE RALLY AND MARCH DURING THE PANDEMIC LONG BEFORE
IT BECAME A NATIONAL MOVEMENT FIGHT.
THE VIRUS NOT THE PEOPLE WAS IT A CHANT FROM CHINATOWN,
PORTSMOUTH SQUARE TO UNION SQUARE RECOGNIZING ITS
SIGNIFICANCE IN 2022 THIS SMITHSONIAN ARCHIVE THE 20 BY
FOUR FOOT RED VINYL BANNER FROM THE RALLY FOR ITS PERMANENT
COLLECTION MR. DALEY WORKED WITH CHINESE HOSPITAL
AND FORMER SUPERVISOR AND PESKIN AND CREATED THE VERY
FIRST MOBILE COVID 19 TESTING STATION FOR LOW INCOME SRO
TENANTS IN CHINATOWN. MR. DALEY HAS BEEN PARTNERING
EXTENSIVELY WITH NONPROFIT TO ADVANCE THE WELL-BEING OF LOW
INCOME SENIORS AND FAMILIES INCLUDING PROJECT LIGHT
COLLABORATIONS WITH SOUTH HALL FOR THE ELDERLY TO RAISE
AWARENESS ON CENSUS 2020 AND TAI CHI FOUNDATION TO
DISTRIBUTE FOOD AND CARE PACKAGES TO OUR SENIORS TODAY
HE'S MOVING FULL STEAM FORWARD ON CULTURAL PRESERVATION EFFORT
. >> HE LEADS PILGRIMAGE TO DUTCH
FLAT AND COMA, TWO OF THE LARGEST HISTORIC
CHINESE-AMERICAN SETTLEMENTS AND GOLDEN GATE GOLDEN SPIKE
NATIONAL PARK TO HONOR THE THOUSANDS OF CHINESE-AMERICAN
LABORERS WHO SACRIFICED THEIR LIVES TO THE CONSTRUCTION OF
THE RAILROAD. >> AS A LEADER OF CHINATOWN
HISTORICAL AND CULTURAL ARTIFACTS COMMITTEE, HE IS ALSO
LEADING A TEAM OF VOLUNTEERS TO PRESERVE ARCHIVE AND ORGANIZE
OVER 30,000 DOCUMENTS. STORE CBAS MEETING HALL HE
HOPES THAT FUTURE GENERATIONS CAN LEARN ABOUT CBA'S CRITICAL
HISTORIC ROLE AND HE DREAMS THAT THE ARTIFACTS CAN BE
DISPLAYED AS CBAS VERY OWN HISTORY MUSEUM I ALSO WANT TO
SAY THAT I WANT TO EXPRESS MY PERSONAL THANKS TO MR. DALEY
DURING MY FIRST TERM WE FIRST TO LANDMARK LINCOLN PARK WHICH
INCLUSIVE A KONG CHAO MEMORIAL AND IN THAT SITE BECAUSE OF MR.
DANG LEE'S WORK WE ARE ABLE TO NOT ONLY CELEBRATE THAT SITE TO
HONOR OUR ANCESTOR BUT WE ALSO WERE ABLE TO BRING TOGETHER THE
LEGION OF HONOR LEADERS LINCOLN PARK, COMMUNITY LEADERS, EVEN
THE GOLF COURSE LEADERS TO COME TOGETHER TO TO REALLY HONOR THE
KONG CHAO MEMORIAL. SO WITH THAT IN CELEBRATION OF
AAPI HERITAGE MONTH THANK YOU MR. DALEY, FOR ALL YOUR
CONTRIBUTION AND LEADERSHIP FOR OUR COMMUNITY.
BUT BEFORE YOU SPEAK, SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU
AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CONNIE CHEN FOR CELEBRATING MR. DENNY
. THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
EVERYTHING THAT YOU HAVE DONE AND YOU CONTINUE TO DO
AND SUPPORTING OUR COMMUNITY AND PRESERVING ARTS AND CULTURE
AND AND HISTORY AND ALSO I WANT TO SPEAK ON BEHALF OF THE LEE'S
FAMILY ASSOCIATION AT YOUR INSTRUMENTAL LEADERSHIP IN ALL
THIS YEARS AND ALSO CONTINUE TO PROVIDE A PLATFORM
AND UPLIFTING THE YOUNGER GENERATION WITHIN THE FAMILIES
ASSOCIATION AND CONTINUE TO PROVIDE A LOT OF OPPORTUNITY TO
NURTURE THE YOUNG PEOPLE THIS IS SOMETHING THAT I SEE THAT
THE FAMILY ASSOCIATION UNDER LEADERSHIP'S LAW USE CONTINUE
TO GIVE LOTS OF HOPE TO OUR YOUNGER GENERATION BUT AT THE
SAME TIME CONTINUE TO HAVE LOTS OF PROGRAM THAT IS CARING FOR
OUR OLDER GENERATION TO MAKE SURE THAT WE BRIDGE THE GAP
THAT WE OUR CULTURE, OUR HERITAGE AND OUR HISTORY
CONTINUE TO ABLE TO CARRY FORWARD.
>> AND I WOULD WITH THAT I KNOW THAT YOU ARE IN THE FAN
AND ALSO IN THE BACK BUT I ALSO WANT TO RECOGNIZE YOUR WIFE WAS
HERE TODAY WITH YOU AND I THINK WITHOUT YOU KNOW THE FAMILY
SUPPORT IT'S ALSO IMPOSSIBLE FOR FOR A LOT OF THE GOOD WORK
YOUR AND YOUR LEADERSHIP TO BE CONTINUE TO BE OUTSIDE AND TO
BE A MENTOR FOR THE YOUNGER GENERATION IN MY MIND.
SO I ALSO WANT TO EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE AND APPRECIATION
AND OUR LOVE TO YOUR WIFE. >> THANK YOU PERSONALLY
RECENTLY I HAD BORDERLINE HIGH THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SAUDER
THANK YOU BOARD PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU FOR
BRINGING THIS RECOGNITION FOR MR. DINGLEY BEFORE US.
IT IS WELL-DESERVED AND YOU KNOW THERE'S HARDLY A AN
INITIATIVE IN CHINATOWN OR AN ORGANIZATION IN CHINATOWN THAT
YOU ARE NOT INVOLVED WITH THAT YOU ARE NOT TOUCHING, THAT YOU
ARE NOT LEADING IN SOME WAY. SO IT'S BEEN INCREDIBLE TO
LEARN OF YOUR WORK, OF YOUR CONTRIBUTIONS AND ALL YOU'VE
DONE IN THE PAST BUT ALL YOU HAVE ON THE HORIZON.
I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING WITH YOU AND I THINK YOU'RE A
PERFECT EXAMPLE OF THE CITY AND THE COMMUNITY WORKING
TOGETHER. >> SO THANK YOU
AND CONGRATULATIONS GIL AND NOW THE FLOOR IS YOURS.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON, MR. CHAIRMAN.
ARE THE MEMBERS ACTING AS A GUESS AND ALL THE CONFERENCE?
I'M SO GRATEFUL I HAVE THIS GREAT HONOR TO ME AND I'M JUST
SURPRISED AND THEN I JUST THAT THE LONG RECORD OF PEOPLE
AND JUST DO WHATEVER I HAVE TO DO FOR THE COMMUNITY
AND BECAUSE AS THE MEMBER OF THE UNION ASSOCIATION AND CCP
FOR ALSO MY FAMILY AND THE ASSOCIATIONS AND THE THING I
JUST LEARNED FROM MY HISTORY AS A CPA THAT HE HAS 175 YEARS
HISTORY ALWAYS A FIGHT FOR THE THE RIGHT FOR THE HUMAN RACE
ALL THE THINGS I'VE LIKE A LONG CAME OUR CASE AND EQUAL
PROTECTION UNDER THE LAW OR BILINGUAL EDUCATION AND ALSO IS
OUR POLITICAL SILENCE ALL KIND OF CASE TO EDUCATE ME HOW TO
LEARN HOW TO SURF THE COMMITTEE COMMITTEE AND I JUST WANT TO
FOLLOW OUR INSIST AS THE FOOTSTEPS EXTEND OUR SPIRIT SO
CONTINUE THOSE SERVICE TO THE PEOPLE FOR THE COMMUNITY.
THAT'S MY GOAL AND ALSO SEBAS CHEN MENTIONED THAT CONG TOLL
MEMORIAL I STILL GOT A LOT OF WORK TO BE DONE I MY GYM IS
WILL BE SET UP THE MONUMENT OVER THERE TO SHOW THAT 180
YEARS AGO WHAT OUR INSISTENCE OVER THERE TO HOW THEY FIGHT
FOR THE FOR THE LIVING FOR THEIR LIFE THAT'S MY MY GOAL MY
MISSION I WISH EVERYBODY CAN HELP ME TO DO THAT TO CONTINUE
TO SERVICE IN THE COMMUNITY. THANK YOU VERY MUCH
THE DISTRICT TO SUPERVISOR CHERYL WELL THANK YOU PRESIDENT
GENTLEMAN AND COLLEAGUES. IT IS MY ABSOLUTE HONOR TO
COMMEND LESLIE KING FOR OUTSTANDING DEDICATION AS
CO-LEADER OF THE AVILA'S STREET CORRIDOR NEIGHBORHOOD
ASSOCIATION. LESLIE, PLEASE COME UP TO THE
PODIUM NOW. >> LESLIE WAS BORN AND RAISED
RIGHT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO. COMMUNITY ORGANIZER, ARTS
ADVOCATE AND NOW A MOTHER OF TWO WHO BRINGS CREATIVITY,
WARMTH AND A DEEP COMMITMENT TO CIVIC LIFE IN EVERYTHING THAT
SHE DOES NOW OFTEN IN THESE COMMENDATIONS WE RECOGNIZE
PEOPLE FOR DECADES AND DECADES OF SERVICE FOR LIVING IN A
NEIGHBORHOOD OR BEING PART OF AN ORGANIZATION FOR 30 YEARS,
50 YEARS. BUT I THINK IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT
TO REMEMBER THAT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO THE MAGIC OF THIS
CITY IS THE MIX OF PEOPLE WHO ARE NEWER TO A NEIGHBORHOOD
WITH THE PEOPLE WHO'VE BEEN THERE FOREVER.
AND I AM SO PROUD TO BE ABLE TO CELEBRATE YOU BECAUSE YOU DOVE
IN WITH BOTH FEET AND BOTH HANDS AND NOW BOTH CHILDREN
ALONG WITH SARAH WITHOUT WHOM NONE OF THIS WOULD BE POSSIBLE.
I KNOW I'LL SAY IT SO YOU DON'T HAVE TO KNOW.
YOU DO HAVE TO. BUT SINCE MOVING TO A VILLAGE
STREET IN THE FALL OF 2024, LESLIE WASTED NO TIME
ORGANIZING BLOCK PARTIES, NEIGHBORHOOD ASSOCIATIONS
AND FOSTERING THE GENUINE CONNECTIONS AMONG LONGTIME
RESIDENTS AND NEWCOMERS ALIKE. THE AVILA STREET CORRIDOR
NEIGHBORHOOD ASSOCIATION IS A NEWLY FORMED BUT ALREADY
BELOVED ORGANIZATION DEDICATED TO BUILDING COMMUNITY
AND CONNECTION IN THE MARINA BRINGING NEIGHBORS TOGETHER
THROUGH THOSE SHARED MOMENTS, THOSE CASUAL GET TOGETHERS
AND THE NOW SIGNATURE ANNUAL EVENTS THAT ARE TRADITIONS.
NOW AMONG THOSE TRADITIONS IS THE FAMOUS OF ILLUSTRATED
HALLOWEEN CELEBRATION THAT LESLIE HAS NOW HELPED TAKE OVER
THE ORGANIZATION OF BRINGING JOY AND A SENSE OF BELONGING TO
RESIDENTS OF ALL AGES. PROFESSIONALLY, LESLIE WORKS
IN BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT AND MARKETING AT LOOKING UP
ARTS, A SAN FRANCISCO NONPROFIT SUPPORTING LARGE SCALE
INTERACTIVE ART WHERE SHE ALSO SERVES ON THE BOARD OF
DIRECTORS. >> HER BACKGROUND IN EVENT
MANAGEMENT SPANS MAJOR COMMUNITY FESTIVALS INCLUDING
THE MOUNTAIN VIEW ART AND WINE FESTIVAL AS WELL AS CORPORATE
EVENTS HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO EXPERIENCE SHE NOW CHANNELS
DIRECTLY INTO STRENGTHENING HER OWN NEIGHBORHOOD BUT BEYOND
COMMUNITY ORGANIZING LIKE LESLIE QUIETLY GIVES BACK BY
MENTORING INDIVIDUALS AND STUDENTS NAVIGATING THE JOB
SEARCH PROCESS REFLECTING HER BELIEF IN LIFTING OTHERS AS SHE
RISES HERSELF, LESLIE EMBODIES THE SPIRIT OF WHAT MAKES SAN
FRANCISCO'S NEIGHBORHOODS THRIVE NEIGHBORS SHOWING UP FOR
ONE ANOTHER BUILDING TRADITIONS WORTH CELEBRATING BUILDING
FAMILIES RIGHT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO AND TURNING THEIR
STREETS INTO COMMUNITIES. >> SO LESLIE, ON BEHALF OF THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, THANK YOU FOR YOUR ENERGY.
YEAH, I KNOW I'M EXCITED TOO. I AGREE.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR CREATIVITY AND FOR YOUR COMMITMENT TO
MAKING A VILLAGE STREET IN THIS CITY A WARMER, MORE CONNECTED
PLACE TO CALL HOME. THANK YOU SO MUCH TO SUPERVISOR
CHERYL AND THE CITY FOR THIS HONOR.
>> THAT'S MY DAUGHTER TALIA. SHE'S VERY EXCITED TO BE HERE
WITH US TODAY. UM, I WAS BORN AND RAISED
IN SAN FRANCISCO AS YOU MENTIONED AND PRIOR TO LAST
YEAR I'VE NEVER REALLY KNOWN ANY OF MY NEIGHBORS.
UM, I ALSO COULD HAVE NEVER TOLD YOU THE NAME OF A DISTRICT
SUPERVISOR OF MINE. >> WE MOVED TO A VILLAGE STREET
A YEAR AND A HALF AGO AND THAT'S BECAUSE WE TOOK OUR
DAUGHTER TRICK OR TREATING ON A VILLA WHEN SHE WAS THREE WEEKS
OLD AND WE FELL IN LOVE AND THOUGHT IT WOULD BE A
REALLY AMAZING COMMUNITY FOR OUR FAMILY TO BE IN.
MY PARENTS LIVE IN THE MARINA AS WELL AND YOU KNOW WE WERE SO
EXCITED TO MOVE THERE BUT WE WERE ACTUALLY KIND OF A LITTLE
DISAPPOINTED WHEN I GOT THERE AND I STARTED MEETING A COUPLE
OF MY NEIGHBORS AND LEARNED THAT BASICALLY NO ONE ON MY
BLOCK KNEW EACH OTHER EXCEPT FOR MAYBE THE PERSON WHO LIVED
NEXT DOOR. >> SO I HAPPENED TO SEE THIS
RANDOM POSTING FROM THE CIVIC JOY FUND HOW THEY WERE DOING
SOMETHING CALLED A BLOCK PARTY FUND AND I THOUGHT IT WOULD BE
A COOL THING SO I APPLIED FOR IT AND WE GOT THIS GRANT AND WE
WERE ABLE TO HOST OUR FIRST BLOCK PARTY ON A REAL STREET.
WE GOT SUPPORT FROM CHERYL'S OFFICE AND WE WERE ABLE TO
LAUNCH A REALLY AWESOME PARTY. WE'VE NOW HAD TWO BIG BLOCK
PARTIES THE FALL ONE WHICH HAD OVER 500 PEOPLE AND THE SMALLER
ONE THIS PAST WEEKEND WITH ABOUT 200 PEOPLE.
>> BUT WE NOW HAVE SO MANY MORE PEOPLE IN OUR NEIGHBORHOOD THAT
KNOW EACH OTHER. PEOPLE TELL ME THIS CONSTANTLY
. I HAVE NEIGHBORS WHO'VE LIVED
ON OUR BLOG FOR 30 YEARS WHO CONSTANT LEE TELL ME THAT THEY
KNOW MORE PEOPLE NOW FROM ME AND FROM THE LAST YEAR THAN
THEY HAVE IN THREE DECADES OF LIVING ON OUR BLOCK.
>> UM I PERSONALLY CAN'T EVEN WALK FROM MY HOUSE TO CHESTNUT
STREET WITHOUT IT SOMETIMES TAKING AN HOUR BECAUSE I RUN
INTO SO MANY NEIGHBORS THAT WANT TO CHAT UM, MY KIDS GET TO
GROW UP KNOWING THE OTHER KIDS ON THEIR BLOCK AND YOU KNOW FOR
ME LIKE I HAD A LOT OF FRIENDS THAT WERE LEAVING SAN FRANCISCO
AND A LOT OF IT WAS YOU KNOW, THEY WERE DRAWN TO THE IDEA OF
THIS COMMUNITY. YOU OFTEN FIND IN THE SUBURBS
WHERE YOU KNOW, YOU KIND OF KNOW YOUR NEIGHBORS AND I NEVER
EVER EVER WANT TO LEAVE CISCO OR MY HOUSE FOR THAT MATTER.
SO I PLAN TO STAY FOREVER AND I'M JUST REALLY HAPPY TO BE
A PART OF CREATING THIS COMMUNITY.
WHAT'S REALLY AMAZING IS THAT THIS CONNECTION DIDN'T STOP AT
THE BLOCK PARTY WE NOW HAVE AN ACTIVE NEIGHBORHOOD ASSOCIATION
WITH A WHATSAPP GROUP THAT HAS 60 PEOPLE A DIRECTORY OF 120
HOUSEHOLDS OLDS. WE'VE BEEN SHARING DISASTER
PREPAREDNESS RESOURCES. WE WERE ABLE TO WARN NEIGHBORS
WHEN THERE WAS THREE HOME BREAK INS ON OUR STREET IN A SHORT
PERIOD OF TIME OR YESTERDAY MY NEIGHBOR TEXTED ME WHEN SHE SAW
I WAS PARKED IN STREET CLEANING AND I WAS ABLE TO AVOID GETTING
A TICKET SOMETHING THAT OTHERWISE NEVER WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED IF YOU DIDN'T KNOW WHO THAT WHO I WAS ANYWAYS, THE
GATHERINGS ARE JUST TO ME MORE ABOUT MORE THAN JUST ONE FUN
AFTERNOON AND I THINK CREATING THE FOUNDATION FOR REAL
COMMUNITY AND KNOWING YOUR NEIGHBORS IS A HUGE PART OF
THAT. >> SO I'LL JUST SAY THANK YOU
TO CIVIC JOY FUN AND THE CITY AND MY FAMILY AND FOR JUST THE
CITY FOR RECOGNIZING HOW POWERFUL SOMETHING AS SIMPLE AS
YOU KNOW, NEIGHBORS COMING TOGETHER CAN BE.
>> SO THANK YOU. ARE YOU DONE?
WE HAVE TO TAKE A PICTURE JUST WITH
DISTRICT THREE SUPERVISOR SAUDER THANK YOU.
>> PRESIDENT MANDOLIN COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE THE
HONOR OF WELCOMING HARRISON ANDERSON TO OUR CHAMBERS FOR A
SPECIAL RECOGNITION. HARRISON WOULD YOU PLEASE COME
ON UP AND JOIN US? >> HARRISON IS A DISTRICT THREE
DAD WHO CHANNELED HIS LOVE FOR WALKING INTO SOMETHING BIGGER
RECENTLY AFTER TRAGEDY STRUCK ON SATURDAY MARCH 14TH,
HARRISON LACED UP HIS SHOES AND STARTED WALKING.
HE DIDN'T STOP UNTIL 50 MILES LATER.
ALONG THE WAY HE KEPT FOLLOWERS UPDATED ON INSTAGRAM, TALKED TO
NEARLY A DOZEN REPORTERS AND HELPED RAISE THOUSANDS OF
DOLLARS FOR SAFE STREETS ADVOCACY WITH WALK SAN
FRANCISCO. HARRISON STARTED WALKING
BECAUSE HE WAS SHAKEN BY THE DEATH OF A TODDLER IN MISSION
BAY KILLED IN FEBRUARY AT A LARGE DANGEROUS INTERSECTION.
THIS DEATH CAME AMIDST A DEVASTATING START TO THE YEAR
IN WHICH WE'VE SEEN FAR TOO MANY PEOPLE KILLED ON OUR
STREETS WILL SIMPLY TRYING TO MOVE ABOUT THEIR DAY.
>> HARRISON STARTED HIS LONG JOURNEY AT 7 A.M. IN DISTRICT
THREE OF COURSE CHOOSING THE BEAUTIFUL IN A CULBREATH PARK
ABOVE RUSSIAN HILL TO DEPART FROM.
HE ZIGZAGGED ACROSS THE CITY AND THEN ENDED BACK AT UNICO
WORTH PARK JUST BEFORE MIDNIGHT AFTER HAVING WALKED 50 MILES
ACROSS THE CITY. HARRISON THANK YOU FOR TAKING
ACTION. WHEN MANY SEE TRAGEDY THEY LOOK
AWAY. BUT YOU STEP FORWARD.
YOU PUT ONE FOOT IN FRONT OF THE OTHER AND YOU GOT A LOT OF
ATTENTION OUT OF IT. YOUR ACTION GENERATED THOUSANDS
IN DONATIONS FOR SAFE STREET ADVOCACY WITH WALK US F AND CUT
HEADLINES ACROSS THE BAY AREA TO DRAW ATTENTION AND REMIND US
OF THE CRISIS OF DANGEROUS STREETS.
I KNOW THIS IS PERSONAL TO YOU AS YOU HAVE A YOUNG SON
AND WALK AND TAKE PUBLIC TRANSIT THROUGHOUT THE CITY
BECAUSE OF YOUR WORK. YOUR SON WILL HAVE A SAFER CITY
TO MOVE THROUGH WHEN HE GROWS UP.
YOU HAVE MY WORD I WILL DO EVERYTHING ON THIS BOARD TO
HELP WITH THAT AS WELL. >> THANK YOU HARRISON.
I LOVE TO HEAR SOME OF THE HIGHLIGHTS OF YOUR WALK.
IN A MOMENT AND HEAR WHAT YOU SAW ON THAT 50 MILES ACROSS OUR
CITY. WE USUALLY GIVE PEOPLE FLOWERS
WHEN WE RECOGNIZE THEM. WE THOUGHT AFTER ALL THAT
WALKING YOU COULD USE A NEW PAIR OF SOCKS OR WE'RE GOING TO
GIVE YOU SOME NEW SAN FRANCISCO SOCKS.
BUT FOR NOW ON INVITE YOU TO SAY A FEW WORDS AND AGAIN TELL
US ABOUT THAT WALK. >> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. SUPERVISOR MEMBERS OF THE BOARD
AND EVERYBODY HERE FIRST WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU SO MUCH TO
EVERYBODY THAT DONATED TO THE FUNDRAISER FOR THE WALK SAN
FRANCISCO WE RAISED NEARLY $6,000 FROM OVER 100 DIFFERENT
DONATIONS AND I HEARD FROM PEOPLE NOT JUST HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO BUT ACROSS THE COUNTRY ABOUT HOW PEDESTRIAN
SAFETY HAS AFFECTED THEM AS A NATION.
WE'VE SPENT THE LAST EIGHT YEARS PRIORITIZING
INFRASTRUCTURE FOR CARS, NOT PEOPLE AND IT'S AN EVIDENT
PROBLEM ACROSS THE NATION. SO I KNOW THAT THIS RESONATED
WITH A LOT OF PEOPLE LAST FALL THE SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE
REPORTED THAT SAN FRANCISCO HAS THE LOWEST PERCENTAGE OF
CHILDREN OF ANY MAJOR AMERICAN CITY AT JUST ABOUT 13%.
NOW WHENEVER I HEAR FROM FELLOW PARENTS REASONS WHY THEY HAVE
CHILDREN AND LEAVE THE CITY, IT TENDS TO FALL INTO TWO CAMPS.
NUMBER ONE IS AFFORDABILITY AND THEN NUMBER TWO IS SAFETY
AND THE SAFETY ISSUES THAT THEY BRING UP TO ME AREN'T CRIME OR
THE UNHOUSED THINGS THAT WE TYPICALLY THINK OF.
IT'S HAVING SAFE SPACES TO BE OUTSIDE PLAYING WITH THEIR KIDS
AND SO MUCH OF THAT HAS TO DO WITH OUR SIDEWALKS AND OUR
INTERSECTIONS AND THE BEHAVIOR OF DRIVERS.
SO I AM COUNTING ON YOU MEMBERS OF THIS BOARD TO DO EVERYTHING
YOU CAN TO BRING SAFER STREETS FOR FAMILIES LIKE MINE BECAUSE
WE ARE THE FUTURE OF SAN FRANCISCO.
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE. I BELIEVE IT WAS TENNESSEE
WILLIAMS THAT SAID THERE'S THREE AMERICAN CITIES NEW YORK,
SAN FRANCISCO, NEW ORLEANS AND EVERYWHERE ELSE IT'S
CLEVELAND. WE'RE NOT HEADED TO CLEVELAND
SO PLEASE DON'T MAKE ME WALK 60 MILES NEXT TIME LET'S LET'S
HAVE 50 BE ENOUGH. THANK YOU
. >> NEXT UP DISTRICT FOUR
SUPERVISOR WONG THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MADELINE.
GOOD AFTERNOON, COLLEAGUES. IT IS MY HONOR TODAY TO PRESENT
COMMENDATIONS TO TWO REMARKABLE LEADERS IN THE SUNSETS CULTURAL
AND DANCE COMMUNITY MS.. AMY CAI AND MISS LISA ZOU.
THEIR DEDICATION, CREATIVITY AND COMMUNITY SPIRIT HAVE
ENRICHED THE LIVES OF COUNTLESS RESIDENTS IN OUR CITY.
MANY IN OUR CHINESE AND AAPI COMMUNITIES ARE FAMILIAR WITH
PLAZA DANCING AND ITS ROOTS IN BOTH TRADITIONAL AND MODERN
FOLK DANCE FORMS. WHAT BEGAN AS A SIMPLE
AND ACCESSIBLE WAY FOR NEIGHBORS ESPECIALLY SENIORS TO
STAY ACTIVE HAS GROWN INTO A CULTURAL PHENOMENON ACROSS
CITIES WORLDWIDE. BEYOND MOVEMENT AND MUSIC,
PLAZA DANCING BRINGS PEOPLE TOGETHER.
IT SUPPORTS PHYSICAL AND MENTAL WELL-BEING CREATES BELONGING
AND KEEPS CULTURAL TRADITIONS ALIVE IN THE PUBLIC SQUARE HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO. MS..
AMY CAI HAS BEEN A PIONEER IN THIS MOVEMENT.
SHE FOUNDED THE SAN FRANCISCO SQUARE DANCE TEAM IN 2009
AND BEGAN GATHERING RESIDENTS IN THE WEST SUNSET PLAYGROUND
FOR OUTDOOR PRACTICE. FOR THE PAST 17 YEARS HER
LEADERSHIP HAS BUILT MORE THAN JUST A DANCE TEAM.
SHE HAS BUILT A COMMUNITY UNDER HER GUIDANCE, THE GROUP HAS
BECOME A PLACE OF JOY, CONNECTION AND CULTURAL
EXCHANGE. ONE OF THE DANCERS WHO GREW
UNDER AMY'S MENTORSHIP IS MS.. LISA ZOU.
LISA BEGAN AS A MEMBER OF AMY'S TEAM AND THROUGH HER TALENT
AND DEDICATION SHE BECAME THE TEAM COACH OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
HAPPY DANCE TEAM. SHE CONTINUES TO CARRY FORWARD
THE VALUES OF INCLUSIVITY, DISCIPLINE AND CULTURAL PRIDE
THAT PLAZA DANCING REPRESENTS. BOTH AMY AND LISA HAVE
CONTRIBUTED IMMENSELY TO UPLIFTING COMMUNITY SPIRIT
THROUGHOUT THE SUNSET AND BEYOND.
THEIR WORK HAS ENCOURAGED HEALTHY MOVEMENT AMONG SENIORS
,SUPPORTED EMOTIONAL WELL-BEING, FOSTERED
INTERGENERATIONAL FRIENDSHIPS AND SHARED CHINESE DANCE
CULTURE WITH THE BROADER SAN FRANCISCO COMMUNITY.
TODAY WE ALSO RECOGNIZE THEIR VISIONARY LEADERSHIP
IN ORGANIZING THE UPCOMING DANCE LEGACY SAN FRANCISCO
PLAZA DANCE DANCING GRAND PERFORMANCE EVENT TAKING PLACE
THIS SATURDAY MAY 9TH AT ST END OF THE SUNSET.
AS PART OF THIS AS PART OF OUR CITY'S CELEBRATION OF AAPI
HERITAGE MONTH, THIS EVENT WILL BRING TOGETHER PERFORMERS
ACROSS THE CHINESE DANCE AND PLAZA DANCE COMMUNITY TO
HONOR TRADITION, CELEBRATE DIVERSITY AND SHOWCASE THE
ARTISTRY THAT THRIVES IN OUR NEIGHBORHOODS.
I WANT TO EXTEND MY WARM WELCOME TO ALL OF YOU TO
PARTICIPATE AT THIS EVENT FOR THEIR YEARS OF SERVICE,
CULTURAL LEADERSHIP AND THEIR DEEP COMMITMENT TO STRENGTHEN
THEIR COMMUNITY THROUGH DANCE WE PROUDLY OFFERS TODAY IS
COMMENDATIONS TO MS.. AMY CAI AND MS. LISA XU.
WE THANK YOU FOR ALL YOU HAVE DONE AND CONTINUE TO DO FOR OUR
CITY. >> DR. O SUPER SUPERVISOR CHEN.
>> THANK YOU BOB. I'M SO LISA TO WHOM I IMITATE
L.A. THEY COME WITHOUT L.A. THE YELLOW GIRL SUE THOMAS.
HE
WON. >> DEAR SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS AMY TAI. I'M 80 YEARS OLD AND I HAVE
ESTABLISHED THE SAN FRANCISCO SQUARE DANCE TEAM FOR 17 YEARS.
AND THROUGH THESE YEARS WE'VE BEEN PRACTICING WEEKLY AT THE
ORTEGA LIBRARY SUNSET WEST SUNSET SQUARE OR PLAYGROUND.
>> AND FOR THIS COMING SATURDAY, THE PERFORMANCE WILL
INVOLVE 13 GROUPS AND ALSO MORE THAN 200 PERFORMERS.
SO WE WELCOME EVERY ONE OF YOU TO PARTICIPATE IN THIS AAPI
CELEBRATION AND ENCOURAGE US FOR LEARNING AND THRIVING
AND UPLIFTING THE COMMUNITY TOGETHER
. >> MY NAME IS LISA SHI AND I'M
THE TEAM COACH AND LEADER AT THE SAN FRANCISCO HAPPY DANCE
TEAM. AND EVERY WEEK EVERY WEDNESDAY
WE OFFER A FREE COMMUNITY DANCE TEACHING CLASSES IN THE SUNSET
DISTRICT AND WE ARE VERY WELL RECEIVED AND LOVED BY THE
DIVERSE COMMUNITY AND OUR TEAM'S MISSION IS TO SPREAD
POSITIVE ENERGY AND ALSO CULTIVATE FRIENDSHIPS, UNITY,
HARMONY IN THE COMMUNITY AS WELL AS TO PROMOTE THE VERY
BEAUTIFUL AND ELEGANT CHINESE FOLK DANCE AND SQUARE DANCE
THINGS IN THIS COMMUNITY AND THROUGHOUT THE US.
SO THIS SATURDAY AGAIN WE SINCERELY INVITE EVERY ONE OF
YOU TO PARTICIPATE AT THE SING AND CELEBRATION.
>> IT'S AT 1 P.M. ON SATURDAY MAY NINTH.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH TO LISA. THANK YOU.
OKAY. I CAN SEE YOU.
>> I DON'T THINK ANYONE DISTRICT SIX SUPERVISOR DORSEY
THANK YOU PRESIDENT MANDOLIN. >> COLLEAGUES AS WE KICK OFF
SAN FRANCISCO SMALL BUSINESS WEEK IT IS MY HONOR TO
RECOGNIZE A WELL-LOVED SOMA ESTABLISHMENT BEANIES BEANIES
KITCHEN. >> WITH THIS COMMENDATION WE
ALSO CELEBRATE THE INSPIRING STORY OF ITS CO-OWNERS BEANIE
AND SUNITA. TWO IMMIGRANT WOMEN FROM
KATHMANDU, NEPAL GIFTED RESTAURATEURS WHOSE SKILLS
CONTRIBUTE SO MUCH TO OUR CITY'S CULINARY SCENE.
IN BENNY'S KITCHEN THEY HAVE CREATED A SPACE WHERE GUESTS
ARE WELCOME LIKE FAMILY AND INTRODUCED TO THE RICH
TRADITIONS OF NEPALI CUISINE. HAVING HAD MANY OPPORTUNITIES
TO VISIT BENNY'S MYSELF, I CAN SAY FIRSTHAND HOW EXCEPTIONAL
THE FOOD IS AS ARE THE DRINKS THEIR MOMOS, HOWEVER, ARE TRULY
STAND OUT FRESH FLAVORFUL, MADE WITH UNMISTAKABLE CARE
AND SINGLE HANDEDLY RESPONSIBLE FOR EARNING BENNY THE MONIKER
FROM THE SFGATE FOOD CRITIC. AS THE BAY AREA'S QUEEN OF
MOMOS THEIR MANGO LASSI IS ALSO A TREAT.
THE PERFECT BALANCE OF SWEETNESS AND TRADITION JUST
GREAT TRY TO IN FACT. NEVER BEFORE HAVE I GROWN SO
HUNGRY JUST DELIVERING A COMMENDATION OR WRITING ONE
IN THIS CHAMBER BENNY'S KITCHENS LEAGUE LEGIONS OF FANS
ATTEST TO ITS EXCELLENCE IN A MULTITUDE OF WAYS FROM ITS FIVE
STAR REVIEWS ONLINE TO ITS NEIGHBORHOOD WIDE BUZZ.
THIS IS AN EXEMPLARY SMALL BUSINESS NOT SOLELY BECAUSE OF
THEIR GREAT FOOD BUT ALSO BECAUSE OF THE LOVE
AND NEIGHBORLY NESS THESE TWO REMARKABLE WOMEN OFFER TO THEIR
CUSTOMERS AND TO THE COMMUNITY AT LARGE.
BENNY ENCINITAS JOURNEY AS IMMIGRANT BUSINESS OWNERS
REFLECTS RESILIENCE, DETERMINATION AND A DEEP
COMMITMENT TO OUR NEIGHBORHOOD AND ITS DIVERSE COMMUNITIES.
THEY HAVE BUILT A SUCCESSFUL SMALL BUSINESS THAT ALSO BRINGS
PEOPLE TOGETHER ACROSS CULTURES AND BACKGROUNDS.
THEIR RESTAURANT HAS BECOME A CHERISHED PART OF THE
NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE STORIES ARE SHARED.
FRIENDSHIPS ARE FORMED. GUESTS FEEL AT HOME AND WHERE
WE OCCASIONALLY HAVE NEIGHBORHOOD MEETINGS.
THEIR SUCCESS IN SOMA WHERE THERE ARE SO MANY SMALL
BUSINESSES LIKE RESTAURANTS THAT HAVE REALLY FACED ONGOING
CHALLENGES IN RECENT YEARS MERITS A SPECIAL COMMENDATION.
>> FOR THIS SMALL BUSINESS WEEK.
DESPITE NEIGHBORHOOD CHALLENGES, BENNY AND SUNITA
HAVE REMAINED STEADY AND COMMITTED CONTINUING TO
INVEST IN THEIR BUSINESS, THEIR CUSTOMERS AND THE COMMUNITY
AROUND THEM. THEIR PERSEVERANCE SPEAKS NOT
ONLY TO THEIR STRENGTHS AS ENTREPRENEURS BUT ALSO TO THEIR
BELIEF IN SOMA AND ITS FUTURE. BENNY AND SUNITA THEY'VE
ENRICHED OUR CITY IN COUNTLESS WAYS THROUGH YOUR FOOD, YOUR
HOSPITALITY, YOUR NEIGHBORLINESS AS AN EXAMPLE.
I AM SO GRATEFUL FOR THE OPPORTUNITY TO BE YOUR
SUPERVISOR TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMITMENT TO THE CITY WE
ALL LOVE AND TO CELEBRATE THE CONTINUED SUCCESS OF YOUR
BUSINESS FOR MANY YEARS TO COME .
AS WE RECOGNIZE AND CELEBRATE SMALL BUSINESS WEEK, I AM PROUD
TO HONOR BENNY'S KITCHEN WITH THIS RECOGNITION FOR ITS
ENDURING CONTRIBUTIONS TO SOMA AND TO SAN FRANCISCO.
>> CONGRATULATIONS, MR.. AND THANK YOU.
GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE. THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS
HONOR, SUPERVISORS. IT REALLY MEANS A LOT TO ME.
>> MY SISTER AND MY ENTIRE TEAM OF BENNY'S KITCHEN.
WE STARTED WITH A SIMPLE VERY, VERY SIMPLE GOAL TO SHARE
AUTHENTIC NEPALESE FOOD AND BRING OUR CULTURE TO A
COMMUNITY HERE IN LOVELY, LOVELY, LOVELY, LOVELY, LOVELY
SAN FRANCISCO. >> THIS YEAR MARKS OUR 14 YEARS
OF SERVICE AND CONTINUES TO SOMA, A GRADUATE FROM LA
COCINA, A NONPROFIT ORGANIZATION AND THIS
RECOGNITION ENCOURAGED US TO KEEP GROW AND GROW AND KEEP ON
GOING. I WANT TO THANK YOU MY TEAM,
OUR CUSTOMERS AND EVERYONE WHO HAS SUPPORTED US ALONG THE WAY.
WE WOULDN'T BE HERE WITHOUT YOU AND THE ENTIRE TEAM AND OUR
LOVELY CLIENTS. A SPECIAL THANK.
THANK YOU TO MONASH VERY GRATEFUL AND SUPERVISOR DOROTHY
VERY GRATEFUL. >> AND OF COURSE URBAN ACADEMY
FOR YOUR TREMENDOUS SUPPORT AND IN SOMA COMMUNITY.
THANK YOU AGAIN FOR BELIEVING IN SMALL BUSINESS LIKE US
AND THE IMMIGRANT WOMAN WHO WILL KEEP ON GOING.
>> THANK YOU
. >> ALL RIGHT.
WITH THAT, MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR 3 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER
PLEASE CALL ITEMS 26 AND 27 TOGETHER ITEMS 26 AND 27 ARE
HEARING AND RESOLUTION TO CONSIDER AND APPROVE A REPORT
OF ASSESSMENT COSTS SUBMITTED BY THE DIRECTOR OF PUBLIC WORKS
FOR INSPECTION AND OR REPAIR OF BLIGHTED PROPERTIES ORDERED TO
BE PERFORMED BY SAID DIRECTOR WITH THE COST THEREOF HAVING
BEEN PAID OUT PAID FOR OUT OF A BLIGHT ABATEMENT FUND RATE WE
HAVE BEFORE US A HEARING ON THE REPORT OF ASSESSMENT OF COSTS
FOR BLIGHTED PROPERTIES. AND WE'RE GOING TO BE HEARING
AND I GUESS I'M OPENING THAT HEARING AND THEN WE ARE FIRST
GOING TO HEAR FROM THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. PRESIDENT MADALYN AND MEMBERS
OF THE BOARD. MY NAME IS WOULD YOU CHUNG
REPRESENTING SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC WORKS CODE ENFORCEMENT.
ARTICLE 23 OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC WORKS CODE KNOWN AS THE
GRAFFITI REMOVAL AND ABATEMENT ORDINANCE AND CHAPTER 80 OF THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE KNOWN AS THE COMMUNITY PRESERVATION
AND BLIGHT REDUCTION ACT REQUIRES PROPERTY OWNERS TO
MAINTAIN THEIR PROPERTY IN A SAFE AND LIGHT FREE CONDITION.
THE CODE REQUIRES PUBLIC WORKS TO INSPECT GRAFFITI AND NOTIFY
PROPERTY OWNERS TO ABATE THE GRAFFITI WITHIN 30 DAYS WHEN
GRAFFITI IS OBSERVED, PUBLIC WORKS ISSUES A NOTICE OF
VIOLATION AND NOTIFIES PROPERTY OWNERS BY POSTING A PHYSICAL
NOTICE ON THE PROPERTY AND SENDING OUT COPIES OF THE
NOTICE VIA USPS. THE NOTICE OF VIOLATION
CONTAINS INFORMATION ON HOW TO CONTACT THE GRAFFITI UNIT, HOW
TO REQUEST A HARDSHIP HEARING, HOW TO REQUEST AN EXTENSION OF
ADDITIONAL TIME AS NEEDED DATE STAMP COLORED PHOTOS SHOWING
THE EXTENT AND LOCATION OF THE GRAFFITI IS AVAILABLE ON
REQUEST OR EVERY NOTICE OF VIOLATION POSTED THE GRAFFITI
UNIT MAKES A CONSIDERABLE EFFORT TO RESEARCH PROPERTY
OWNERSHIP AND MAKES COURTESY CALLS OR SENSE COURTESY EMAILS
TO PROPERTY OWNERS, PROPERTY REPRESENTATIVES AND OR PROPERTY
TENANTS ALERTING THEM OF THE GRAFFITI VANDALISM ON THEIR
PROPERTY AND ABATEMENT REQUIREMENTS.
>> IF AFTER THE 30 DAY PERIOD HAS PASSED AND THE GRAFFITI HAS
NOT BEEN REMOVED WE WILL POST A COURTESY FINAL NOTICE INFORMING
THE PROPERTY OWNER THAT A BLIGHT FEE WILL BE LEVIED
SHOULD THE GRAFFITI NOT BE REMOVED.
A BLIGHT NOTICES THEN ISSUED TO THE PROPERTY AND A BLIGHT FEE
IS ASSESSED IF THE GRAFFITI IS NOT REMOVE WITHIN 15 DAYS OF
THE BLIGHT POSTING THE CITY CAN ELECT TO HIRE A CONTRACTOR TO
REMOVE THE GRAFFITI ON PRIVATE PROPERTY AT THE ADDITIONAL
EXPENSE TO THE PROPERTY OWNER. THE INTENTION OF THIS DIVISION
IS NOT TO COLLECT FEES BUT TO ENSURE THAT GRAFFITI IS REMOVED
IN A TIMELY MANNER. HOWEVER, WHEN A PROPERTY OWNER
FAILS TO PAY THE FLIGHT FEE OR THE FEES RELATED TO THE
ABATEMENT COSTS, PUBLIC WORKS WILL SUBMIT AN ASSESSMENT FOR
THE OVERDUE AMOUNT TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS FOR
CONSIDERATION TO INCLUDE AN INDEX OR REGULAR TAX BILL ON AN
ANNUAL BASIS. SINCE THE LAST HEARING IN MAY
OF 2025 UP UNTIL DECEMBER 31ST OF 2025 3298 NOTICES OF
VIOLATIONS WITHOUT FEES WERE ASSESSED WERE ISSUED.
OF THOSE LOCATIONS 110 OR 3% WERE NOT ABATED IN A TIMELY
MANNER AND ASSESSED APPLY FOR 20 ONE OF THE 110 OR 19% OF
BITE FEES WERE PAID. A TOTAL OF FOUR HARDSHIP
HEARINGS WERE REQUESTED IN WHICH 11 INDIVIDUAL CASES
WERE REVIEWED A TOTAL OF 82 UNPAID INVOICES WERE SUBMITTED
FOR YOUR INITIAL CONSIDERATION AS OF MAY 5TH 2026 INVOICES
TOTALING AT $9,480 WERE REMOVED FROM THE ORIGINAL LIST THROUGH
PAYMENTS MADE IN RECENT MONTHS. 20 OF THE 82 INVOICES WERE PAID
ROUGHLY COMING TO 24% $7,900 RECOVERED OUT OF 32,000
AND $192 WHICH IS ABOUT 22% OF FOUR INVOICES WERE WAIVED
TOTALING 15,580. >> THEREFORE THE REPORT WE ARE
SUBMITTING FOR YOUR CONSIDERATION TODAY HAS 58
INVOICES TOTALING $22,712 INCLUDING THE TOP PERCENT
ADMINISTRATIVE FEE AS OF 12 P.M. TODAY.
IT IS HERE THAT THE DEPARTMENT REQUESTS THE BOARD'S APPROVAL
OF THE LIST FOR INSPECTION AND REPAIR OF BLIGHTED
PROPERTIES. >> THANK YOU.
I DON'T SEE ANY COMMENTS OR QUESTIONS FROM COLLEAGUES
AND SO I BELIEVE WE WILL OPEN THIS ITEM UP FOR PUBLIC
COMMENTS. >> IF YOU'RE A MEMBER OF THE
PUBLIC WHO WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK ON ITEMS 26 OR 27, PLEASE COME
UP TO THE PODIUM IF THERE'S MORE THAN ONE PERSON LINE UP ON
YOUR RIGHT. OUR LEFT?
>> YEAH. COME RIGHT.
COME ON UP. >> GOOD AFTERNOON, SIR.
I'M ONE OF THE SIGHTED OWNERS AND MY OVERSIGHT OF THE
NOTATION OF THE GRAFFITI I ACTUALLY CALLED TO TRY TO GET
SOME GUIDANCE BUT I DIDN'T GET A REPLY ON THE ON THE LAST
NOTICED THAT THEY POSTED ON ME I WAS REQUESTED THAT I COME
IN HERE. I ASK I ASKED ONE OF THE PUBLIC
WORKS INSPECTORS BECAUSE I DID NOT SEE ANY GRAFFITI IN MY
PROPERTY. I TOOK A PICTURE OF MY PROPERTY
TODAY I DID FIND A LITTLE DRAWING ON A LITTLE BRICK WHICH
WAS VERY SMALL AND I CLEAN THAT UP.
IT WAS PENCIL BUT AS I TALKED TO AN INSPECTOR TODAY HE SHOWED
ME A LITTLE TAG AT THE BOTTOM OF ONE OF THE BRICKS WHICH I
COMPLETELY OVERLOOKED SO I ASKED FOR LENIENCY ON MY
CITATION. I WILL TAKE CARE OF THAT.
MY OVERSIGHT WAS NOT TO BE ABLE TO LOOK AT THOSE PICTURES, WAS
NOT ABLE TO LOOK AT THE PICTURES.
SO I ASK FOR LENIENCY ON THIS ITEM.
>> ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. >> FOLKS ARE GOING TO HAVE WE
HAVE WE GOT A LINE OVER THERE SO FEEL FREE TO LINE UP
AND DEPARTMENT STAFF ARE HERE AND CAN TALK TO PEOPLE AND WHAT
WE WILL BE ASKING THEM TO TALK TO PEOPLE OUTSIDE THE CHAMBER
WHEN PUBLIC COMMENT IS OVER CAN WE HAVE OUR NEXT PERSON
SUPERVISORS? GOOD AFTERNOON.
MY NAME'S ALAN KWONG NOT ALAN LONG YEAH PEOPLE ASKED ME IF I
MIGHT GO FOR THE CENSOR SUPERVISOR.
I SAID NO THAT'S WONG. MY NAME IS QUAN SO YEAH I
REPRESENT A AND ASSOCIATION IN CHINATOWN CALL YANG
BENEVOLENT ASSOCIATION AND THEY OWN THIS BUILDING ON 19 AND 12
OUT AND THIS YEAR 2026 I WAS AWARDED THE PRESIDENT OF THE
ASSOCIATION AND RIGHT AFTER I BECAME PRESIDENT I WAS HANDED
OVER A LOT OF LETTERS FROM YEAH GRAFFITI FROM THE HEALTH
DEPARTMENT BECAUSE YEAH A LOT OF THE ASSOCIATION MEMBERS THEY
DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON. THEY SAY WHY WE HAVE TO PAY
WELL THAT'S THE THE SOME CISCO LAW ORDINANCE WE HAVE TO YOU
KNOW GO BY THAT SO SO THIS TIME I WOULD LIKE TO ASK FOR A
WAIVER OF THIS GRAFFITI BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER I TOOK OVER WE DID
A LOT OF PAINTING AGAIN RIGHT AFTER WE REPAINT THE GRAFFITI.
ANOTHER ONE WILL GO UP AGAIN THIS 19 AND TELL ABOUT THE
BUILDING IS ON 20 2004 19 AVENUE SO WE GOT I TALKED TO
JOSE RAMIREZ. HE TOLD ME THAT THERE WAS A ART
PROGRAM THAT I CAN, YOU KNOW, REQUEST THE CITY TO DO SOME
WORK ON IT. SO THAT'S WHAT I DID TWO WEEKS
AGO AND THEN WE GOT APPROVED. >> SO I'M JUST THINKING IF WE
CAN GET THAT THE WAY THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WE'RE PROVIDING EVERYONE THE SAME TWO MINUTES.
WE DO HAVE MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC WORKS STAFF THAT YOU'LL
BE ABLE TO TALK TO ABOUT YOUR PROPERTIES AND FOR MEMBERS OF
PUBLIC WHO MAY NOT WANT TO MAKE PUBLIC COMMENT AND YOU CAN ALSO
TALK TO STAFF WHO ARE HERE TO TALK.
>> PLEASE PROCEED. >> HELLO, MY NAME IS JOHN
LITTLE. I HAVE BEEN COMING HERE TO TALK
ABOUT 969 ONE OF VISTA AVENUE WEST.
>> THIS PROPERTY IS PARTICULARLY IGNORED.
THE PROPERTY OWNER HAS BEEN NEGLIGENT WHERE THERE ARE ALSO
LEANS ON WATER AND TRASH AND I HAVE BEEN OCCUPYING AND BEATING
THE GRAFFITI AT THIS PROPERTY AS OF TWO SUNDAYS AGO ON APRIL
19TH WE ENTER THE PROPERTY HAVE BEEN OCCUPYING IT AND IT HAS
BEEN PAINTED OVER. >> IT HAS BEEN TAGGED AGAIN
TWICE AND REPAINTED OVER WITHIN A SINGLE DAY AND EVERY SINGLE
ONE OF THE DOZEN NEARBY NEIGHBORS OR STORE OWNERS HOMES
WALKS BY AND SEEN AS DOING THIS HAS BEEN IN SUPPORT.
>> WE'RE PLANNING TO WE'VE PAID FOR A THREE OR SO GALLONS OF
PAINT OUT OF OUR OWN POCKETS IN A COUPLE OF FRIENDS, SOME OF
WHOM ARE IN ATTENDANCE AND PLANNING TO PAY THIS FEE
OUT OF OUR OWN POCKETS. >> HOWEVER, IF IT IS WITHIN THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS DISCRETIONARY POWER WE WOULD
LOVE TO SEE THAT FEE WAIVED OR REDUCED SINCE WE HAVE AS OF
OCCUPYING THE PROPERTY ABATED THIS GRAFFITI PARTICULARLY
QUICKLY AND SENT AN EMAIL TO S.F. PUBLIC WORKS AS DIRECTED
ON THEIR WEBSITE. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON.
>> MY NAME IS WANTED THOMAS AND I'M HERE ON BEHALF OF MERCY
HOUSING THE PROPERTY IS LOCATED AT 130 ONE SIXTH STREET.
IT'S IT'S ON THE MINNA ALLEY THERE.
WE DO HAVE A MURAL. WE DID HAVE A MURAL ON THE SIDE
OF OUR BUILDING. IT WAS GRAFFITI TO THE POINT
WHERE IT WAS GOING TO COST US AN ASTRONOMICAL AMOUNT OF MONEY
TO TRY TO RESTORE THE MURAL. THE MURAL HAS SINCE BEEN
PAINTED OVER. THE GRAFFITI HAS BEEN REMOVED
AND WE'RE ASKING IF THE FEE COULD BE WAIVED FOR US.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> NEXT SPEAKER.
>> MY NAME IS SALVADOR VASQUEZ AND I'M THE OWNER OF THE
PROPERTY OF 2987 TO 2995 24TH STREET AND WELL I BEEN IN THAT
BUSINESS IN THAT BUILDING SINCE 1975 AND I'VE BEEN TRYING TO
CATCH UP OR TO BRING THAT BUILDING TO THE CODE.
>> IT WAS FOR A WHILE THAT IT WAS EVERY TWO MONTHS OR SO LAST
YEAR I PAINTED THE GRAFFITI OR I PAINTED AND THE NEXT DAY IT
WAS DONE AGAIN AND I WELL I FINALLY GOT THIS LETTER WITH A
FINE OR SOMETHING THAT I NEVER GOT BEFORE BUT AGAIN MY
BUILDING I TRIED THE BEST THAT I COULD HAVE AND I.
>> I TRIED RIGHT NOW I MADE SOME PICTURES OF IT BECAUSE THE
WORST THAT I DONE WAS THAT THEY WENT AS THE LADY BEFORE SAID
THAT THEY NEVER PAINTED OVER THE MURALS BUT LAST YEAR THEY
WENT EVEN OVER THEM. >> SO I WAS ALL FOR A GRANT OR
TWO $2,500 THROUGH THE CITY TO REPAINTED AND I ASKED WHAT DO I
HAVE TO DO? >> THEY TOLD ME THAT I HAD TO
HAVE A POLICE REPORT. I HAVE TO HAVE SO MANY THINGS
THAT I COULDN'T EVEN GET POSSIBLY BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
WHO WHO IS DOING THIS THING AND IT'S DONE OVERNIGHT AND HOW
CAN I WATCH OVER OR DO ANYTHING I DON'T KNOW.
BUT AGAIN, AS I SAID, I HAVE PICTURES OF THE BUILDING RIGHT
NOW AS IT IS UNFORTUNATE FOR THE LAST COUPLE OF WEEKS OR
THREE WEEKS NOBODY HAVE DONE ANY GRAFFITI BUT IN THE PAST
THAT WAS DONE I PAINTED IT AND THE NEXT DAY IT WAS DONE
AGAIN. I JUST NOTICED ACROSS THE
STREET THERE IS A BUILDING THERE.
I SAW THE MAN PAINTING IT. >> I SAW AND I HAVE A PICTURE
OF THAT HERE TOO. >> I THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. >> I APOLOGIZE FOR CUTTING YOU
OFF. WE ARE PROVIDING EVERYONE THE
SAME TWO MINUTES YOU WILL HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK WITH
THE PUBLIC WORKS STAFF NEXT SPEAKER HELLO.
THANK YOU FOR LETTING GIVE ME A CHANCE TO SPEAK IN THESE
CHAMBERS. MY NAME'S NICOLE, OKLAHOMA.
DORCAS HI. ON THE PROPERTY AT 15 DEBOSE
AVENUE LIKE THE OTHER FELLOW PROPERTY OWNERS.
YOU KNOW I'VE GONE AND PAINTED OVER THE GRAFFITI AND BECAUSE
OF MY BUILDING'S PROXIMITY TO A SKATE PARK ACROSS THE STREET
WHICH IS ALSO GRAFFITIED WITH MURALS ALL PAINT IT
AND LITERALLY THE VERY NEXT DAY IT'LL BE COVERED AGAIN AND I'LL
PAINT IT AGAIN AND IT'LL BE COVERED AGAIN IN GRAFFITI ROCK
PAINT IT AGAIN AND IT WILL BE COVERED WITH MURALS AND SO I'VE
DONE SOME THINGS TO MITIGATE THAT WOOD FOR THE LIGHTING I'VE
PUT UP LIGHTING TO LIGHT UP BOTH THE FRONT OF MY PROPERTY,
THE NEIGHBORS PROPERTY TO THE LEFT AND THE NEIGHBOR'S
PROPERTY TO THE RIGHT WHICH THE NEIGHBORS APPRECIATE BECAUSE
WHEN I GET TAGGED THEY GET TAGGED AS WELL.
YOU KNOW I'M SIX GENERATION SAN FRANCISCO AND THE THIS CITY
RUNS IN MY DNA AND I WOULD LOVE TO GET SOME KIND OF RESPITE FOR
THE FINE AND YOU KNOW, I COULD COME BACK TOMORROW.
I'LL SHOW YOU THAT I'LL PAINT THE BUILDING TOMORROW AND THE
VERY NEXT DAY IT'LL BE GRAFFITI AGAIN.
AND IT'S A IT'S A BIG ISSUE AND IT'S HARD IT'S A HARDSHIP
ON PROPERTY OWNERS AND SO HOPEFULLY YOU'LL ALLOW SOME
KIND OF MITIGATION FOR THE FINE.
I APPRECIATE IT. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ARE THERE ANY OTHER INDIVIDUALS
WHO LIKE TO PROVIDE COMMENT ON ITEMS 26 OR 27?
>> SEE NONE, MR. PRESIDENT. ALL RIGHT.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED AND SEE NO OTHER NAMES ON THE
ROSTER. THIS PUBLIC HEARING ITEM NUMBER
26 HAS BEEN HEARD AND IS NOW FILED AND WE DO HAVE OUR HAS
OUR PUBLIC WORKS STAFF GONE OUT INTO THE YEP THEY'RE OUTSIDE SO
IF PEOPLE OR THEY'RE GOING OUTSIDE PEOPLE WANT TO ENGAGE
AND TALK WITH MR. CHANG ABOUT ASSESSMENT PLEASE DO AND WE'LL
COME BACK TO THIS WE'LL COME BACK TO ITEM 27 LATER IN THE
MEETING. >> ALL RIGHT.
>> I THINK THEN THAT POSSIBLY WE COULD GO BACK TO ITEM 23,
MADAM CLERK. >> YES.
AND FOR THE PUBLIC THIS ITEM HAS BEEN CALLED ITEM 23 IS THE
RESOLUTION SUPPORTING THE JUNIOR RESERVE OFFICERS
TRAINING CORE SUPERVISOR WONG THANK YOU.
>> APPRECIATE COLLEAGUES SUPERVISOR CHAN AND SUPERVISOR
WALTON FOR BRINGING UP A POTENTIAL FOR SUGGESTIONS
AND AT THIS TIME FOR FOR THE SUGGESTED CHANGES I DON'T THINK
THAT HAVING THE CHANGES WOULD MEET THE ORIGINAL INTENT OF THE
RESOLUTION WHICH IS TO URGE THE SCHOOL DISTRICT TO PRESERVE THE
PROGRAM AS CURRENTLY CONSTITUTED IF THERE ARE
CONCERNS REGARDING BUDGET. >> SO I WOULD NOT LIKE TO SEE
AMENDMENTS AND LIKE TO HAVE IT GO FORWARD.
THIS ITEM HAS BEEN THOROUGHLY DISCUSSED IN COMMITTEE
AND APPRECIATE THE CONVERSATION AND THE TESTIMONY WE HEARD AT
THIS TIME. I RESPECTFULLY ASK FOR YOUR
SUPPORT AND WOULD LIKE TO CALL FOR A VOTE.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU.
AND I JUST WANT TO SAY I RESPECT SUPERVISOR WONG
SUPERVISOR WONG'S CHOICE OF NOT WANTING TO ACCEPT THE
AMENDMENTS. >> I WILL SAY THAT I DON'T FEEL
COMFORTABLE URGING THE SCHOOL DISTRICT TO DO ANYTHING THAT
MAY HAMPER THEIR ABILITY TO BALANCE THE BUDGET.
I AM THE LONE PERSON ON THIS BODY THAT HAS SERVED ON THE
BOARD OF EDUCATION, UNDERSTANDS THE SCHOOL BOARD'S BUDGET
INTRICATELY AND I DEFINITELY KNOW THAT THEY SHOULD HAVE THE
LATITUDE TO BE ABLE TO ADDRESS THEIR BUDGET CONSTRAINTS THE
WAY THEY NEED TO. AGAIN, I THINK THIS IS A
PROGRAM THAT MOST CERTAINLY IS DOING GOOD THINGS WITH GROUPS
OF YOUNG PEOPLE IN THE DISTRICT BUT IT IS A DEPARTMENT OF
JUSTICE PROGRAM AND QUITE FRANKLY IN THE RIGHT WORLD THEY
WOULD BE FUNDING THE PROGRAM IN ITS ENTIRETY.
THE SCHOOL DISTRICT HAS STEPPED UP IN A MAJOR WAY TO MAKE SURE
JROTC OPERATES HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
BUT I DON'T FEEL COMFORTABLE URGING THE DISTRICT TO PRESERVE
ANY PROGRAM THAT IS NOT SPECIFICALLY ACADEMIC WHEN THEY
SAY THEIR FOCUS RIGHT NOW OF COURSE IS TO MAKE SURE THAT THE
40 PLUS THOUSANDS OF STUDENTS RECEIVE A QUALITY EDUCATION.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THIS ITEM ON ITEM 23.
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON NO SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN I MENDELSON
I SUPERVISOR MELGAR I MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I THERE ARE EIGHT EYES IN ONE NO
LESS SUPERVISOR OF WALTON VOTING NO AND THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO BACK TO ROLL CALL.
>> NEXT UP ON ROLL CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS IS SUPERVISOR
CHAN THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU.
>> SUPERVISOR SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES, I AM TODAY CALLING FOR A HEARING TO EXPLORE
OPTIONS ON HOW SAN FRANCISCO CAN BETTER UTILIZE ITS OWN REAL
ESTATE ASSETS TO REVITALIZE OUR MARKET STREET CORRIDOR
AND BETTER LEVERAGE THE DRAW OUR WORKFORCE AND CITIZENRY
WOULD OFFER TO ATTRACT MORE PRIVATE INVESTMENT
AND REINVIGORATE OUR CIVIC CENTER AND OUR DOWNTOWN.
PRIORITY NUMBER ONE IN MY VIEW SHOULD BE RELOCATING OUR HALL
OF JUSTICE TO THE MARKET STREET CORRIDOR THIS MID-TWENTIETH
CENTURY BEHEMOTH WAS FIRST IDENTIFIED AS A SERIOUS SEISMIC
HAZARD IN THE AGNUS ADMINISTRÉ PORTION AND THEN LISTED FOR
DEMOLITION IN THE JORDAN ADMINISTRATION.
AND WE HAVE TEMPTED FATE FAR TOO LONG FOR FAR TOO MANY YEARS
TO ALLOW ITS CLOSURE AND RELOCATION TO LANGUISH
FURTHER. THE HALL OF JUSTICE
ADDITIONALLY REFLECTS THE KIND OF LAND USE DECISION TYPICAL OF
THE MID-TWENTIETH CENTURY WHEN CONVENIENT MEANT OFF THE
HIGHWAY RATHER THAN ON A TRANSIT CORRIDOR.
KNOW THESE DECISIONS HAVE CEASED TO SERVE US WELL IN THE
21ST CENTURY AND THERE THE KIND OF LAND USE PROBLEMS WE NOW
HAVE A ONCE IN A LIFETIME OPPORTUNITY TO SOLVE WITH SOME
OF OUR ADAPTIVE REUSE INITIATIVES.
THERE'S NO REASON WHY THE HALL OF JUSTICE COULDN'T BE
PRIORITIZED AS ONE OF THEM THE REBUILD OR MAJOR REPLACEMENT OF
THE HALL OF JUSTICE RIGHT NOW ACCOUNTS FOR APPROXIMATELY $417
MILLION IN OUR CAPITAL PLAN AND ITS HUNDREDS OF WORKERS
AND THOUSANDS OF VISITORS INCLUDING 30,000 JURORS
ANNUALLY WOULD DOUBTLESS FIND A MARKET STREET LOCATION MORE
ACCESSIBLE AND WOULD COLLECTIVELY BENEFIT THE
NEIGHBORHOOD OF MID-MARKET AND CIVIC CENTER WITH ITS
ECONOMIC ACTIVITY. WE FURTHERMORE DON'T LACK FOR
OPTIONS ON OR NEAR MARKET STREET WHICH COULD INCLUDE THE
SAN FRANCISCO CENTER FIVE M THE OLD MINT WHITCOMB HOTEL TWITTER
BUILDING ONE SOUTH VAN NESS 1455 MARKET AND OTHERS NOTABLY
THE EMPORIUM SITE OF THE SAN FRANCISCO CENTER ONCE HOUSED
THE CALIFORNIA SUPREME COURT 120 YEARS AGO SO ITS
REACTIVATION AS A JUDICIAL DESTINATION FOR THE STATE'S
COURTS COULD BRING ITS HISTORIC USE FULL CIRCLE BEYOND ADAPTIVE
REUSE POLICIES. WE MAY ALSO HAVE AN ACQUISITION
OPTIONS ESPECIALLY IN TERMS OF FEDERAL ASSETS THAT THE TRUMP
ADMINISTRATION AND GSA IDENTIFIED LAST YEAR FOR
POSSIBLE SALE THESE COULD POTENTIALLY INCLUDE 50 NEW
AND PLAZA. YOU MAY ALSO RECALL THAT THE
SPEAKER NANCY PELOSI FEDERAL BUILDING WAS LISTED FOR A TIME
I THINK YOU KNOW HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO WE WOULD WELCOME
IN MID-MARKET A SPEAKER NANCY PELOSI HALL OF JUSTICE IF THAT
WAS SOMETHING THAT WE COULD ACQUIRE.
NEITHER ARE WE LIMITED TO IN THIS DISCUSSION.
TWO TO THE HALL OF JUSTICE ALONE AMONG CIVIC CENTER CIVIC
CENTER APPROPRIATE REAL ESTATE ASSETS THE POLICE ACADEMY WOULD
DO WELL ON OR NEAR MARKET STREET.
I KNOW THAT IS SOMETHING THAT IS WE HAVE ANOTHER REAL ESTATE
ASSET THAT HAS BEEN IN ITS LOCATION FOR A LONG TIME.
THERE ARE DOUBTLESS OTHER REAL ESTATE ASSETS TOO THAT WE COULD
BE LOOKING AT FROM OUR REAL ESTATE DIVISION, OUR OFFICE OF
ECONOMIC AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT THAT WE COULD
EXPLORE AS WELL. I WILL BE INVITING EXPERT
PERSPECTIVE FROM PRIVATE SECTOR PROFESSIONALS IN ADAPTIVE REUSE
PROJECTS INCLUDING SOME WHO ARE HAVE YEARS OF FAMILIARITY WITH
PROJECTS IN SAN FRANCISCO TO WEIGH IN ON HOW WE MIGHT BE
THINKING BETTER AND MORE CREATIVELY TO READ TO LEVERAGE
OUR CITY REAL ESTATE ASSETS AND MAKE SAN FRANCISCO'S MARKET
STREET THE SHOWPLACE IT DESERVES TO BE.
>> YEAH THE REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY
SUPER SUPERVISOR AND WE SUBMIT THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MELGAR
THANK YOU SO MUCH MADAM CLERK TODAY I JUST HAVE AN A MEMORIAL
IN MEMORIAM FOR LARRY MAZOLA SENIOR LARRY MAZOLA SENIOR WAS
A TOWERING FIGURE IN SAN FRANCISCO'S LABOR MOVEMENT
AND A STEADFAST ADVOCATE FOR WORKING PEOPLE.
HE PASSED AWAY AT AGE 82 LEAVING BEHIND A LEGACY DEFINED
BY STRENGTH, LOYALTY AND TRANSFORMATIVE LEADERSHIP.
>> A PROUD NATIVE SON MAZOLA DEVOTED NEARLY FIVE DECADES TO
LOCAL 38 AND THE UNITED ASSOCIATION RISING THROUGH THE
RANKS TO ASSISTANT TRAINING DIRECTOR AND ORGANIZER TO
BUSINESS MANAGER IN FINANCIAL SECRETARY TREASURER WHERE HE
SET A NATIONAL STANDARD FOR WAGES, BENEFITS AND WORKPLACE
SAFETY KNOWN AS THE RELENTLESS FIGHTER WHO NEVER WAVERED
IN DEFENDING HIS MEMBERS, HE HELPED SECURE PROSPERITY
AND DIGNITY FOR THOUSANDS OF CONSTRUCTION WORKERS AND THEIR
FAMILIES. HIS INFLUENCE HIS INFLUENCE
EXTENDED BEYOND THE UNION HALL INTO PUBLIC SERVICE WHERE HE
SERVED WITH DISTINCTION FOR 26 YEARS AS A SAN FRANCISCO
AIRPORT COMMISSIONER INCLUDING 18 YEARS AS PRESIDENT BEFORE
RETIRING IN 2022. ADDITIONALLY, HE SERVED ON THE
GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE COMMISSION. THE RECREATION AND PARKS
COMMISSION SERVED AS VICE PRESIDENT OF A DISTRICT FIVE
VICE PRESIDENT ON THE CALIFORNIA STATE AFL-CIO BOARD
AND AS VICE PRESIDENT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO LABOR COUNCIL
AND THE PRESIDENT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BUILDING
AND CONSTRUCTION TRADES COUNCIL FOR 30 YEARS, MISSOULA'S
ENDURING IMPACT LIVES ON AND THE LIVES THAT HE IMPROVED,
THE INSTITUTIONS HE STRENGTHENED AND BUILD IN THE
CITY THAT HE HELPED TO BUILD. LARRY IS SURVIVED BY HIS WIFE
OF 50 EIGHT YEARS, STEPHANIE, HIS CHILDREN LARRY JUNIOR,
STEVE AND LAURIE AND THEIR SPOUSES AND HIS GRANDCHILDREN
JOEY, NICK, SOPHIA AND STELLA AND HIS SISTER JOANNE ALL HIS
FAVORITE PEOPLE CALLED HIM PAPA.
SERVICES WILL BE HELD ON FRIDAY, MAY 8TH, 2026 AT 10
A.M. AT ST MARY'S CATHEDRAL THROUGH THE PRESIDENT.
I WOULD LOVE IT IF WE COULD CLOSE TODAY'S MEETING FOR THE
WHOLE BOARD IN MEMORY OF LARRY MAZOLA SENIOR ON BEHALF OF ALL
OF US THE REST I SUBMIT THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND I WILL MAKE A MOTION THAT WE DO THAT
ON BEHALF OF THE FULL BOARD AND THERE WE GO.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MELGAR SUPERVISOR SARDAR THANK YOU.
>> COLLEAGUES EARLIER THIS YEAR I INDICATED THAT I WAS DRAFTING
LEGISLATION TO PROHIBIT THE RETAIL SALE OF NITROUS OXIDE
AND TODAY I AM INTRODUCING THIS LEGISLATION I'M DOING SO AFTER
A FEW MONTHS OF PRODUCTIVE CONVERSATIONS TO MAKE SURE WE
CRAFT LEGISLATION THAT WORKS IN RESPONSE TO THIS GROWING
HEALTH CONCERN. THE RECREATIONAL USE OF NITROUS
OXIDE OFTEN REFERRED TO AS LAUGHING GAS OR WHIPPETS HAS
BEEN EXPLODING IN POPULARITY IN SAN FRANCISCO AND ACROSS THE
UNITED STATES. THE PRODUCT IS BEING BRANDED
IN COLORFUL CANISTERS AND MARKETED TO YOUTH UNDER
NAMES LIKE GALAXY GAS, MIAMI MAGIC AND COSMIC GAS.
THIS SHOWS A CLEAR PATTERN OF MANUFACTURERS FOLLOWING THE
PLAYBOOK OF BIG TOBACCO AND VAPE MARKETING DID
DANGEROUS PRODUCTS TO YOUTH AND VULNERABLE POPULATIONS WHEN
INHALED NITROUS OXIDE CAN CAUSE HEALTH COMPLICATIONS INCLUDING
BLOOD CLOTS, NERVE DAMAGE, HEART PALPITATIONS, PARALYSIS
AND IN SOME CASES DEATH. PROLONGED USE CAN ALSO LEAD TO
SPINAL CORD AND BRAIN DAMAGE. >> THE SAN SAN DIEGO COUNTY
SHERIFF'S CRIME LAB HAS NOTED AN UPTICK IN CASES OF SUSPECTED
DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE OF NITROUS OXIDE INCLUDING 18 CAR
CRASHES IN JUST A ONE YEAR PERIOD.
IN A RECENT STUDY FROM THE UNIVERSITY OF MISSISSIPPI
UNDERSCORED THE DANGERS OF NITROUS OXIDE DURING A 578%
INCREASE IN DEATHS BETWEEN 2010 AND 2023.
THE AUTHORS OF THE STUDY POINT TO A RISE IN AVAILABILITY
AND ACCESSIBLE LOCATIONS LIKE GAS STATIONS AND CORNER STORES
AS A REASON FOR THIS SPIKE. SO OUR LEGISLATION FOCUSES ON
RETAIL STORES IN THESE LOCATION AND THESE LOCATIONS.
WELL ALLOWING EXCEPTIONS FOR LEGITIMATE INDUSTRIAL USES SUCH
AS MEDICAL CATERING, RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT.
SINCE A BAN ON NITROUS OXIDE IN THE UK PASSED IN 2023, USAGE
AMONG YOUNG ADULTS IS DOWN BY APPROXIMATELY 60%.
AND ACROSS CALIFORNIA DOZENS OF CITIES OR COUNTIES HAVE
RECENTLY PASSED RETAIL BANS INCLUDING SAN MATEO, SAN JOSE,
SANTA CRUZ, MENDOCINO, HUMBOLDT, NEWPORT, ORANGE
COUNTY AND ANAHEIM. I WANT TO THANK TO THE BELL
IN MY OFFICE FOR HER THOUGHTFUL AND THOROUGH WORK ON THIS.
JAN A CLERK IN THE CITY ATTORNEY'S OFFICE AS WELL.
AND THANK YOU TO THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH AND THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT FOR CONVERSATIONS TO ENSURE EFFECTIVE ENFORCEMENT.
I'M HAPPY TO BE INTRODUCING THIS LEGISLATION TODAY WITH THE
FULL SUPPORT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO MARIN MEDICAL SOCIETY
. I'D ALSO LIKE TO THANK MY
CO-SPONSORS SUPERVISORS WONG, SHERYL AND MELGAR AND THE REST
OF SCHMIDT. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SOUDER
SUPERVISOR SHERYL. >> COLLEAGUES TODAY I'D LIKE TO
ADJOURN OUR MEETING IN MEMORY OF DORIS FISHER, CO-FOUNDER OF
THE GAP, CHAMPION OF EDUCATION AND DEVOTED PHILANTHROPIST
WHOSE VISION HELPED RESHAPE THE AMERICAN RETAIL INDUSTRY
AND WHOSE GENEROSITY CONTINUES TO TRANSFORM LIVES.
>> DORIS PEACEFULLY PASSED AWAY ON SATURDAY AT THE AGE OF 94.
DORIS LEE FEIGENBAUM WAS BORN ON AUGUST 23RD, 1931 IN SAN
FRANCISCO. TO B.J. AND DOROTHY FEIGENBAUM
. >> DORIS ATTENDED THE KATHERINE
DEL MAR BURKE SCHOOL FOR GIRLS IN SAN FRANCISCO AND WENT ON TO
EARN AN ECONOMICS DEGREE FROM STANFORD IN 1953 WHERE SHE
WOULD LATER SERVE ON THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES FROM 1992 TO 2002.
SHE MARRIED DON FISHER IN JULY OF 1953 BEGINNING NOT ONLY A
LIFELONG PARTNERSHIP IN LOVE BUT ONE OF THE MOST
CONSEQUENTIAL ENTREPRENEURIAL COLLABORATORY COLLABORATIONS
IN AMERICAN BUSINESS HISTORY. IN 1969, DORIS AND DON OPENED A
SINGLE STORE ON OCEAN AVENUE IN SAN FRANCISCO SELLING BLUE
JEANS AND RECORDS. THAT STORE BECAME THE GAP, A
NAME NAMED DORIS HERSELF COINED A NOD TO THE GENERATION GAP
AND THE YOUNG CONSUMERS THEY HOPED TO SERVE AS THE COMPANY'S
FASHION MERCHANDIZER FOR NEARLY 40 YEARS.
DORIS WAS BY HER FAMILY'S ACCOUNT THE SPIRITUAL LEADER OF
THE COMPANY'S VALUES AND ITS SENSE OF RESPONSIBILITY TO
OTHERS. >> THE FISHERS BUILT THE GAP
INTO A GLOBAL RETAIL BRAND CHANGING THE WAY AMERICANS
DRESS AND BRINGING AFFORDABLE, WELL-ORGANIZED, ACCESSIBLE
CLOTHING TO NEARLY EVERY SHOPPING MALL AND URBAN RETAIL
DISTRICT IN THE COUNTRY. BUT THE STRAIGHT.
DESPITE HER EXTRAORDINARY SUCCESS, DORIS LIVED PRETTY
CONSISTENTLY DRIVING THE SAME BUICK STATION WAGON YEAR AFTER
YEAR WEARING HER DECADES OLD OUTFITS AND NEVER REALLY
CHANGING TOO MUCH. TOGETHER WITH DON, DORIS BECAME
AN AVID COLLECTOR OF MODERN ART BUILDING THE DORIS AND DONALD
FISHER COLLECTION TO INCLUDE MORE THAN 1100 WORKS BY 185
ARTISTS INCLUDING ANDY WARHOL, ROY LICHTENSTEIN, CHUCK CLOSE
AND ELLSWORTH KELLY. NOW ON PERMANENT DISPLAY AT THE
SAN FRANCISCO MUSEUM OF MODERN ART EDUCATION, THOUGH WAS
PERHAPS DORIS'S DEEPEST PASSION .
>> SHE AND DON DONATED MILLIONS TO SCHOOLS, TEACHER TRAINING
PROGRAMS AND COLLEGE PREP PROGRAMS FOR UNDERSERVED
COMMUNITIES HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO AND ACROSS THE
COUNTRY. >> HER SON BOB SAID SHE GOT
MORE ENJOYMENT SITTING WITH SCHOOLCHILDREN THAN ALMOST
ANYTHING ELSE SHE DID IN HER REMARKABLE LIFE.
DORIS IS SURVIVED BY HER THREE SONS BOB, BILL AND JOHN.
TEN GRANDCHILDREN AND 13 GREAT GRANDCHILDREN.
HER HUSBAND DON PRECEDED HER IN DEATH IN 2009 FROM A SINGLE
STORE IN SAN FRANCISCO TO A GLOBAL BRAND FROM GALLERY WALLS
TO CLASSROOM CHAIRS. DORIS FISHER'S LEGACY IS ONE OF
CREATIVITY, INTEGRITY AND AN ABIDING BELIEF IN THE POTENTIAL
OF PEOPLE. WE EXTEND OUR DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO THE FISHER FAMILY AND ALL WHO MOURN HER
PASSING. MAYOR MEMORY CONTINUE TO
INSPIRE GENERATIONS OF ENTREPRENEURS, EDUCATORS
AND COMMUNITY BUILDERS TO COME. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHERYL.
MR. PRESIDENT, THAT CONCLUDES ROLL CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COULD YOU ADD ME TO SUPERVISOR
CHERYL'S IN MEMORIAM IF HE DOES NOT OBJECT.
YES. ALL RIGHT.
AND WITH THAT, MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT.
>> AT THIS TIME THE BOARD WELCOMES YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT.
PLEASE LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER ALONG
THE CURTAINS. YOU MAY SPEAK TO ITEMS 31
THROUGH 34 WHICH ARE THE ITEMS ON THE FLOOR ADOPTION WITHOUT
COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA AND GENERAL MATTERS NOT ON THE
PUBLISHED AGENDA BUT MUST BE WITHIN THE BOARD SUBJECT MATTER
JURISDICTION. >> ALL OTHER AGENDA CONTENT
WILL HAVE BEEN REPORTED OUT TO THE BOARD BY AN APPROPRIATE
COMMITTEE WHERE THE PUBLIC COMMENT REQUIREMENT OCCURRED.
>> EACH SPEAKER WILL BE PROVIDED TWO MINUTES.
WILL THE FIRST SPEAKER COME FORWARD?
>> HELLO I'M BARBARA BELLA AND I'M SPEAKING YOU TODAY AS A
CIVILIAN AS A CITIZEN. >> ACTIVISTS ONCE AGAIN SEEKING
SUPPORT FOR TO SPONSOR LEGISLATION TO END THE SALE OF
CIGARETS WITH PLASTIC FILTERS. >> MY COLLEAGUE VINCE YOON WHO
WILL SPEAK TO ME IN A MOMENT HAS ORGANIZED OVER 22,020 2000
VOLUNTEERS ACROSS THE CITY. AND FROM THIS WORK HE HAS
CONCLUDED THAT NO DISTRICT IS IMMUNE FROM THE DANGERS AND THE
POLLUTION CAUSED BY CIGARET LITTER.
GIVEN THIS, IF SOMEONE WHO HAS MOBILIZED TENS OF THOUSANDS OF
INDIVIDUALS IS TELLING YOU THAT OUR CLEAN STREETS THAT CLEANING
UP OUR STREETS IS NOT SUFFICIENT BUT THAT ACTUALLY WE
HAVE TO STOP IT AT THE SOURCE THAT SHOULD BE PERSUASIVE ON
ITS OWN. WE CANNOT CLEAN OUR WAY OUT OF
THIS. WE HAVE TO STOP IT AT THE
SOURCE. >> I KNOW EACH OF YOU HAVE
HEARD DAILY FROM CONSTITUENTS THAT YOU WANT A CLEANER CITY,
THAT THEY WANT CLEANER STREETS. BUT TOO OFTEN THIS IS
INTERPRETED AS CLEANING UP AFTER THE MESS.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS NOT JUST CLEAN UP BUT WE NEED THIS
PREVENTION. IF YOU HAVE A LEAK IN YOUR
HOUSE YOU DON'T JUST MOP THE FLOOR.
>> YOU FIX THE PIPE RIGHT NOW WE'RE MOPPING UP CIGARET BUTTS
FROM SIDEWALKS, FROM PARKS, FROM BEACHES.
BUT WE CANNOT STOP THIS TOXIC WASTE.
ENDING THE SALE OF CIGARETS FIXES THE PIPE AT THE SOURCE.
>> OUR EFFORT HAS BROAD SUPPORT.
EIGHT OF THE WORLD'S LEADING EXPERTS ON THIS TOPIC 20 NINE
NEIGHBORHOOD ASSOCIATIONS OVER 5500 PETITIONS SIGNATURES.
MOMENTUM IS BUILDING BEYOND SAN FRANCISCO.
VINCE AND I JUST SPOKE AT THE ILLEGAL DUMPING CONFERENCE
IN OAKLAND AND AFTER OUR PRESENTATION SUPERVISOR NATE
MALEY OF DISTRICT FOUR OF ALAMEDA COUNTY AGREED
AND COMMITTED TO TAKE ON THIS LEGISLATION.
WE CAN DO THIS TOO. I REALLY APPRECIATE THAT
SUPERVISOR SAUTER HAS IS ORDERING THE BLR TO STUDY THE
IMPACTS OF THIS BAN. >> WE HAVE THE SCIENCE
ORDINANCE AND THE CITY WIDE SUPPORT.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HI EVERYONE. VINCE YOU AND OF REFUSE REFUSE
THANK YOU FOR HEARING MY COMMENTS.
YOU HEARD IT BEFORE SO I'M NOT SAYING ANYTHING NEW BECAUSE
EVERYONE KNOWS THAT CIGARET BUTTS ARE THE NUMBER ONE
CONTRIBUTOR TO PLASTIC POLLUTION IN OUR ENVIRONMENT.
VERY EASY TO IGNORE BECAUSE THEY'RE SO SMALL BUT WHEN YOU
MEET A NEW VOLUNTEER WHO JOINS ONE OF OUR CLEANUPS INEVITABLY
THE FIRST THING THEY SAY IS LIKE WOW, I DIDN'T KNOW SO MANY
PEOPLE STILL SMOKED AND SO THEY'RE EVERYWHERE AS I'M
SPENDING THIS TWO MINUTES THERE'S HUNDREDS OF CIGARET
BUTTS BEING LITTERED IN SAN FRANCISCO TENS OF THOUSANDS,
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS ACROSS THE WORLD AND WE JUST CAN'T
STOP IT. I MEAN WE'LL CONTINUE TO GO OUT
THERE. WE'RE AVERAGING ABOUT 500
VOLUNTEERS A WEEK NOW. >> I THINK WE NEED MORE THAN
THAT AND WE'RE DOING OUR BEST. BUT IT'S A SMALL DROP IN THE
BUCKET OF WHAT WE'RE ABLE TO ACCOMPLISH AND THE ONLY WAY TO
HELP US IS REALLY TO DO SOMETHING UPSTREAM SO WE HAVE
THE ABILITY AND POWER AND I'M ENCOURAGING CITIZENS TO COME
OUT AND CLEAN UP WHAT WE CAN BUT THERE'S JUST NO WAY WE CAN
DO IT OURSELVES WITHOUT THE HELP.
SO WE'RE EMPOWERED TO PICK UP THE BUTTS BUT WE DON'T HOLD ANY
POWER TO DO ANYTHING UPSTREAM TO PREVENT THIS WASTE POLLUTION
AND THAT'S WHY WE'VE COME TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
BECAUSE YOU ALL HAVE THE POWER TO DO SO AND I THINK IT'S
INEVITABLE. SUPERVISOR SOUDER WAS LISTING
OFF RATTLING OFF THE NAMES OF COMMUNITIES BANNING NITROUS
OXIDE. I THINK THE SAME THING'S GOING
TO HAPPEN HERE WITH CIGARET BUTTS, PLASTIC CIGARET BUTTS
AND IT'S JUST INEVITABLE AND YOU SEE ALAMEDA COUNTY
INSTANTLY JUMPING ON IT. AND SO WE CAN RATTLE OFF THE
LISTS AND IT'S JUST GOING TO BE A MATTER OF WHERE SAN FRANCISCO
LIES IN THAT LIST. ARE WE GOING TO BE NEAR THE TOP
WITH LEADERS LIKE SANTA CRUZ OR ARE WE GOING TO BE AT THE
BOTTOM WITH OTHER FOLLOWERS? BUT EITHER WAY IT WILL HAPPEN.
IN THE MEANTIME, WE'LL BE PICKING UP BOATS AND IT'S VERY
EASY BECAUSE SANTA CRUZ HAS ALREADY CREATED THE PLAYBOOK.
TARA LEONARD OF THEIR PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT HAS CREATED A
VERY MUCH A TURNKEY WAY FOR US TO INTRODUCE THAT HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO AND SHE'S WILLING TO HOLD YOUR HAND THROUGH IT.
SO WE'RE JUST LOOKING FOR, YOU KNOW, SUPERVISORS WHO WOULD BE
WILLING TO SUPPORT THIS. MELGAR SUPERVISOR MELGAR I
THINK IT GOES GREAT WITH YOUR PAIRS VERY WELL WITH YOUR SMOKE
FREE PATIOS. YOU KNOW THE UNINTENDED
CONSEQUENCE OF THE SMOKE FREE PATIOS IS THEY GO TO THE CURB
AND THEY LITERATE SO I DON'T WANT SERVERS TO GET SECONDHAND
SMOKE. >> BUT THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER HELLO.
TODAY I RECOGNIZE AND REMEMBER THE MISSING AND MURDERED
INDIGENOUS WOMAN GIRLS AND TWO SPIRIT PEOPLE AS WELL AS HAPPY
CINCO DE MAYO AND ASIAN AMERICAN INDIGENOUS NATIVE
HAWAIIAN AND SPECIFIC ISLANDER MONTH.
I HAVE TO ASK WHERE IS THE GOOD JUDGMENT IN A MAYOR A WEALTHY
WHITE MAN ROAMING AROUND THE CITY IN HIS LUXURY RIVIAN JUST
TO BULLY HOMELESS PEOPLE IN PUBLIC?
>> OR EVER? WHERE IS THE GOOD JUDGMENT
AND PUSHING ABSTINENCE ONLY RECOVERY AS THOUGH THE HUMAN
SPECIES IS ONE MONOLITH? >> WHERE IS THE GOOD JUDGMENT
IN CRUELLY CRUELLY IGNORING THE REALITY THAT HUMANS ARE VERY
DIVERSE SO WE NEED VERY DIVERSE OPTIONS AND SOLUTIONS FOR
PEOPLE WITH SUBSTANCE USE DISORDER.
WHERE IS THE GOOD JUDGMENT IN CONTINUING TO THROW MONEY AT
POLICING WHEN SCHOLARSHIP AND COMMUNITY SHOWS POLICING IS
NOT A SILVER BULLET SOLUTION TO SAFETY THAT HOUSING, BASIC
INCOME, FOOD, SOCIAL ENRICHMENT AND SERVICES AND HEALTH CARE
ARE WHAT MAKE A COMMUNITY THRIVE.
>> WHERE IS THE GOOD JUDGMENT IN SLASHING FUNDING TO THESE
SOCIAL SERVICES AND CLOSING HEALTH CLINICS LIKE WHOLE
STREET YOUTH CLINIC, LARKIN STREET YOUTH CLINIC
AND SOUTHEAST MISSION GERIATRIC CLINIC?
>> WHERE IS THE GOOD JUDGMENT IN DEFUNDING BLACK AND OTHER
COMMUNITIES OF COLOR WHEN THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT IS RACIALLY
RESEGREGATING AMERICA? >> WHERE IS THE GOOD JUDGMENT
AND NOT ACTUALLY PUTTING IN A REAL EFFORT?
EFFORTS TO FIGHT THE TRANSGENDER GENOCIDE HAPPENING
IN AMERICA BEING DONE BY THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT AND I AM NOT
RADICAL FOR SAYING THIS AND ACTUAL GENOCIDE PREVENTION
INSTITUTE HAVE SAID THIS IS HAPPENING IN AMERICA.
>> YOU KNOW IT THOUGH BASED OFF OF YOUR ACTIONS IN HERE.
>> TRANS PEOPLE ARE FLEEING VERY VARIOUS PARTS OF THE
COUNTRY TO SAN FRANCISCO. I HAVE HEARD THAT SINCE LAST
YEAR. WE NOW HAVE TWICE AS MANY
TRANSGENDER PEOPLE IN THIS CITY LOOKING FOR REFUGE.
>> WE NEED INVESTMENT IN OUR SURVIVAL.
>> I MEAN, YEAH. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER. >> MY NAME IS BOB HALL AND I'M
SPEAKING ON BEHALF OF KEEP REAL, A GRASSROOTS COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATION REPRESENTING RESIDENTS OF AMAZON IN THE
EXCELSIOR NEIGHBORHOODS. I'M HERE TO ASK THE BOARD TO
INTRODUCE A RESOLUTION INITIATING AN ARTICLE TEN CITY
LANDMARK NOMINATION FOR AMAZON PLAYGROUND BEFORE IT'S TOO
LATE. >> AMAZON ZION IS NOT JUST A
PARK IT'S ONE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S MOST SIGNIFICANT
SURVIVING NEW DEAL LANDSCAPES DESIGNED BY MASTER ARCHITECT
WILLIAM G. MERCHANT WE BUILT BETWEEN 1934
AND 1941 WITH OVER $938,000 IN WPA FUNDING THE LARGEST NEW
DEAL INVESTMENT IN ANY SINGLE SAN FRANCISCO PLAYGROUND.
IT IS A PLACE OF GENUINE HISTORIC IMPORTANCE.
THE CITY'S OWN CULTURAL LANDSCAPE REPORT COMPLETED JUST
LAST YEAR DOCUMENTS THAT SIGNIFICANCE.
AND RIGHT NOW SAN FRANCISCO REC AND PARK IN PARTNERSHIP WITH
THE SAN FRANCISCO GIANTS LIMITED LIABILITY CORPORATION
IS PROPOSING TO DEMOLISH IT OVER 100 WPA ERA TREES.
WP ERA TREES ARE GOING TO BE REMOVED 20 ACRES OF HISTORIC
GRASS REPLACED WITH FAST LED AND ARTIFICIAL TURF
AND EXPANDED PARKING. THE PARK FENCED OFF THE PARK
WILL BE FENCED OFF AND HANDED OVER PRIMARILY TO BASEBALL.
AN OPEN COMMUNITY COMMON SERVING PACIFIC ISLANDER
SENIORS, FAMILIES AND IMMIGRANTS IN A DESIGNATED
ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE NEIGHBORHOOD WILL BE TURNED
INTO A PRIVATE SPORTS COMPLEX. THIS COMMITTEE HAS THE POWER TO
ACT A BOARD RESOLUTION INITIATING ARTICLE TEN
NOMINATIONS TRIGGERS A DEMOLITION STAY THE ONE TOOL
THAT CAN STOP IRREVERSIBLE HARM WHILE THE HISTORIC PRESERVATION
COMMISSION DOES ITS WORK. I'M ASKING THE BOARD TO
INTRODUCE THAT RESOLUTION NOW. CONSTRUCTION IS TARGETED FOR
2027. THE 80 FOOT TALL TREES CANNOT
BE REPLANTED. THE LANDSCAPE CANNOT BE
RESTORED. PLEASE ACT BEFORE SAN FRANCISCO
LOSES THIS COMMUNITY TREASURE FOREVER.
>> THANKS. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER. >> C.
OKAY I'M JUST GOING TO READ OFF THE TOP BECAUSE IT DOESN'T SHOW
RIGHT HERE. >> SO I JUST WANT TO LET PEOPLE
KNOW THAT ON MAY NINTH THERE'S GOING TO BE TWO CLEANUPS IN THE
BAYVIEW. ONE IS GOING TO BE AT 10 A.M.
ON 1605 GERALD'S AVENUE AND THEN THE SECOND ONE IS
GOING TO BE AT FOUR 6:00 AT TWO 2022 LANE STREET AT 50 270
THREE THIRD STREET. >> SO COME ON DOWN.
WE'RE HERE TO CLEAN THE ENVIRONMENT UP.
THERE'S ALSO GOING TO BE A CAREER TRANSITION CONFERENCE
TOMORROW. IF YOU LOOK UP CAREER
TRANSITION CONFERENCE DESIGN YOUR FUTURE WITH EIGHT PLUS
WEB3 IS GOING TO BE ONLINE FROM 530 TO 8:30 P.M. TOMORROW.
IT'S FREE. THERE'S ALSO THE OPPORTUNITY TO
GET A STOREFRONT GRANT. IF YOU GO LOOK AT APPLY FOR A
GRANT TO AN OPEN AS NEW STOREFRONT YOU CAN SEE THAT THE
GRANT OPPORTUNITIES GO FROM ABOUT 50 TO 100,000 OR SO
AND IT'S GOING TO BE IN THE BAYVIEW.
>> THERE'S OTHER AREAS. CHECK IT OUT.
THE APPLICATIONS END ON MAY 29TH SO GET IT IN.
ALSO I'D LIKE TO PROPOSE THAT WE OPEN UP THE CITY CAREER
CENTER DOWNSTAIRS TO NOT JUST INCLUDE CITY WIDE JOBS BUT IF
WE COULD OPEN IT UP TO OPEN IT TO TRAIN PEOPLE FOR OTHER TYPES
OF JOBS BECAUSE RIGHT NOW IT'S NOT A POLICY IN PLACE.
IT'S MORE OF A ADMINISTRATIVE POLICY IN PLACE TO KEEP IT FOR
CITYWIDE JOBS. THERE'S NO LAW ORDINANCE
REQUIRING IT BECAUSE WE KNOW THAT THERE IS SUCH A NEED RIGHT
NOW FOR EMPLOYMENT. LET'S OPEN THAT CAREER CENTER
UP AND LET'S TRY TO PUT SOME CITY STANDARD DESKS IN THERE TO
ACCOMMODATE THOSE WITH DISABILITIES.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER PRESIDENT MAN WOMAN SUPPORTERS.
SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS RICHARD SD PETERSON
AND REALLY REALLY WHY DO I HAVE TO SEE NATIONAL NEWS TO SEE
THAT TWO SUPERVISORS HAVE BEEN ARRESTED AT THE SAN FRANCISCO
AIRPORT? THIS IS VERY EMBARRASSING.
YOU'VE GOT TO REALIZE THE SAN FRANCISCO BAY AREA AND MUCH OF
THE TECH INDUSTRY FOR SURE CERTAINLY ARE NOT ALL BLUE
DEMOCRATS. >> THERE ARE MANY REPUBLICANS
IN THIS CITY AND IN THIS STATE YOU JUST CAN'T IGNORE THAT WHEN
YOU'RE PROTESTING ON CERTAIN ISSUES.
EVERYBODY CAN BE AGAINST ICE. NOBODY WANTS ICE TO RUN RUN
RAMPANT OVER OUR CITY OR OVER OUR CITIZENS.
>> BUT REALLY WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN STOPPING
TRAFFIC AT THE AIRPORT AND MOTORCYCLES STOPPING
TRAFFIC ON THE BAY BRIDGE? IS IT THE POLITICAL IDEAL
ENERGY? >> I REALLY DON'T HAVE THAT
MUCH MORE TO SAY EXCEPT AS ONE ADDED THING AS COLUMBO WOULD
SAY. I'M REALLY CONCERNED ABOUT THE
PGE IN HERE AND THE COLLABORATION WITH THE CITY
EVEN THOUGH THE CITY IS TRYING TO TAKE OVER THE ELECTRICAL
PORTION PGE AND ME. >> BUT THE BILLS ON GAS ARE
JUST ASTRONOMICAL. I'VE HAD A COTTAGE FOR OVER 50
YEARS AND IT'S GONE FROM $25 UNINSULATED AND NOW IT'S $100
SIMPLY FOR GAS. AND IT'S BEEN INSULATED AND I
DON'T DO ANY LAUNDRY AND IT'S JUST HOT WATER.
SO GET A HOLD OF PGE AND WE ARE REALLY DISAPPOINTED.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ARE THERE ANY OTHER INDIVIDUALS
WHO WOULD LIKE TO PROVIDE GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT?
>> SEEING NONE, MR. PRESIDENT. ALL RIGHT.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED. >> AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO
BACK TO ITEM 27. >> YES.
FOR MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC THIS ITEM HAS BEEN CALLED IT IS THE
RESOLUTION APPROVING THE REPORT OF ASSESSMENT COSTS FOR
BLIGHTED PROPERTIES. >> THAT AFTERNOON PRESENT
AMENDMENT MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. >> SO THANK YOU FOR THE
OPPORTUNITY TO RESOLVE THOSE MATTERS WITH THE WITH THE
CONSTITUENTS. IT WAS PRODUCTIVE.
WE WILL BE WAIVING IN GOOD FAITH THE SEVEN MEMBERS FROM
THE PUBLIC AND THEIR FINES ASSESSED.
WE WILL PROVIDE YOU WITH A UPDATED I BELIEVE WITH MORE OF
A RED REDLINED LIST WAS PROVIDED TO THE CLERK AND WE
WILL PROVIDE YOU A TRUE UP TO DATE LIST TOMORROW MORNING ONCE
WE HAVE ASSESSED IN A MATTER OF THE LAST FEW HOURS WE DID HAVE
A FEW EMAILS THAT CAME IN WHICH WE WOULD LIKE TO GET RESOLVED
PRIOR TO FINAL APPROVAL FROM YOURSELVES.
>> THANK YOU. ALL RIGHT.
I THINK WE HAVE AN UPDATED REPORT.
>> YES, THE WE ARE MAKING COPIES BUT THE ADDRESS IS TO BE
STRICKEN FROM THE LIST WILL BE 533 1233 AVENUE 969 BUENA VISTA
AVENUE WEST 130 ONE SIXTH STREET 1131 MISSION STREET 2404
19 AVENUE 2987 24TH STREET 15 DEBOSE AVENUE 200 POTRERO
AVENUE 960 POTRERO AVENUE AND 1271 POTRERO AVENUE.
OKAY SO COLLEAGUE CAN WE ACCEPT THE AMENDMENTS TO THE REPORT
WITHOUT OBJECTION? >> SEEING NO OBJECTION, THOSE
CHANGES ARE ACCEPTED. >> THEN MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE RESOLUTION WITH THE AMENDED
REPORT? >> YES.
AND ITEM 27 SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I.
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I. SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MANDARIN HAI MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MELGAR I
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL
EITHER NINE NICE ALL RIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION ITEM 27 IS
ADOPTED WITH THE AMENDED REPORT AND WITH THAT MADAME CLERK
LET'S GO TO THE FOUR ADOPTION COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA
ITEMS 31 TO 30 FOUR ITEMS 30 ONE THROUGH 34 WERE INTRODUCED
FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS
REQUIRED FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE
ANY SUPERVISOR MAY REQUIRE RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE
TO GO TO COMMITTEE. ANYBODY WANT TO SEVER ANYTHING
COLLEAGUES I AM GOING TO SEVER 34 TO BRIEFLY SPEAK ON IT
AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR I JUST WANTED TO BE ADDED AS A
CO-SPONSOR TO ITEM 32 PLEASE. >> ALL RIGHT.
THE CLERK I THINK HAS NOTED THAT AND MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU
CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS 3132 AND 33 ON ITEMS 3132 AND 33.
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN HIGH
MANDARIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER
SUTTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EITHER NINE NICE WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM 34 ITEM NUMBER 34 IS A RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING MAY 2026
AS JEWISH AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH AND MAY 9TH THROUGH THE
16TH 2026 IS SAN FRANCISCO JEWISH WEEK IN THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK
COLLEAGUES THIS IS A COMBO RESOLUTION FOR JEWISH AMERICAN
HERITAGE MONTH AND SAN FRANCISCO JEWISH WEEK.
AGAIN THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR YOUR CO-SPONSOR SHIP
SUPERVISOR MILLER AND I HAVE BEEN ALTERNATING DOING THIS
AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR GRACIE FOR YOUR CO-SPONSORSHIP AS WELL
AS FOLKS KNOW JEWISH IMMIGRANTS FIRST ARRIVED IN SAN FRANCISCO
DURING THE GOLD RUSH MANY FLEEING PERSECUTION IN EUROPE
AND FINDING HERE WHAT SO MANY WERE DENIED ELSEWHERE
OPPORTUNITY TO COMMUNITY AND ACCEPTANCE BY THE 1870S SAN
FRANCISCO IS HOME TO THE SECOND LARGEST JEWISH POPULATION
IN THE UNITED STATES. THESE EARLY RESIDENTS HELPED
SHAPE THE CITY AS MERCHANTS, CIVIC LEADERS
AND PHILANTHROPISTS ESTABLISHING COMMUNITY
INSTITUTIONS AND LAYING THE FOUNDATION FOR GENERATIONS TO
COME. AND THAT LEGACY CONTINUES TODAY
AS THE JEWISH COMMUNITY REMAINS DEEPLY ENGAGED IN CIVIC LIFE
WORKING TO BUILD A MORE JUST INCLUSIVE AND COMPASSIONATE SAN
FRANCISCO SAN FRANCISCO JEWISH WEEK IS IN ITS SECOND YEAR
BROUGHT TO US BY VALUE CULTURE AND ADAM SWIG THE CELEBRATION
HIGHLIGHTS JEWISH CULTURE IN SMALL BUSINESSES, CHEFS
AND ARTISTS AND THERE WILL BE DAILY EVENTS DURING THE WEEK
FROM VALKYRIES JEWISH HERITAGE NIGHT TO ROBOT SHABBAT AND A
TASTE OF S.F. JEWISH AND SO HAPPY TO CALL ATTENTION TO BOTH
OF THOSE AND FACTS IN FACT MR. SWIG AND VALUE CULTURE ARE
HAVING A PRESS ANNOUNCEMENT RIGHT NOW WHICH FOLKS CAN HEAD
OVER TO AFTER THIS IF THEY WOULD LIKE TO.
AND WITH THAT I BELIEVE WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM.
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS
ADOPTED. >> AND MADAM CLERK COULD YOU
PLEASE WELL KNOW DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
>> WE HAVE NO IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS TODAY THEN COULD YOU
PLEASE READ THE IN MEMORIAM? YESTERDAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS
ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR WANG FOR THE LATE MR. JIM GARCIA
AND ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND THE ENTIRE BOARD FOR
THE LATE MR. LARRY MAZOLA SENIOR AND ON BEHALF OF
SUPERVISOR CHERYL AND MEN'S WOMEN FOR THE LATE MRS. DORIS
LEE FISHER. ALL RIGHT.
COLLEAGUES, I THINK THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA
MADAM CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US
TODAY? >> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS
FOR TODAY. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
THEN WE ARE ADJOURNED